[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
COLTON OGDEN: All right, welcome to GD50, Lecture 5.
科尔顿·奥格登：好的 欢迎来到GD50 第5堂课
Today's topic is The Legend of Zelda, as you can see on the screen there.
今天的主题是塞尔达的传说 正如你在屏幕上看到的那样
A very iconic game.
一款非常标志性的游戏
Last week we did Super Mario Bros, which is arguably the most iconic video game
上周 我们制作了《超级马里奥兄弟》 它可以说是最具标志性的视频游戏
of all time.
史无前例的
Legend of Zelda is a close contender.
塞尔达传奇是一个势均力敌的竞争者
Even now, just like with Mario, they're producing very wonderful games.
即使是现在 就像马里奥一样 他们也在制作非常精彩的比赛
I think last year Breath of the Wild took all the, I forget which
我想去年《野性的呼吸》夺走了所有的 我忘了是哪一个
ceremony it was, or award sort of show.
这是一场颁奖典礼 或者说颁奖典礼
But it took like every award possible.
但它几乎囊括了所有可能的奖项
Just last year, the latest Zelda, the Breath of the Wild.
就在去年 最新的塞尔达 野性的呼吸
So it feels sort of apropos to talk about Legend of Zelda in that context
因此 在这样的背景下谈论塞尔达传奇感觉有点不合时宜
as well.
也是
Here's a screenshot of the original Legend of Zelda.
以下是原版《塞尔达传奇》的截图
It was an NES title, just like Super Mario Bros--
这是NES的头衔 就像超级马里奥兄弟一样--
just like most games of its time, tile based.
就像它那个时代的大多数游戏一样 以瓷砖为基础
You can sort of see how the surroundings are sort of layered tiles bit by bit.
你可以在某种程度上看到周围是如何一点点地分层的瓷砖
The goal of the game overall was to sort of explore this open world, which
这个游戏的总体目标是探索这个开放的世界 这
is kind of a first of its kind.
这在这方面还是头一回
You controlled Link, shown at the very bottom there.
您控制了Link 如最下面所示
You had a sword, yo had bombs, you had arrows.
你有剑 你有炸弹 你有箭
You want to go find rubies, you went through dungeons.
你想去找红宝石 你得穿过地牢
You slayed monsters and bosses, and then ultimately the goal
你杀死了怪物和头目 然后最终的目标
was to obtain the Triforce which is shown at the very top left and right
是为了获得左上角和右上角所示的三重力
of the slide here.
在这里的幻灯片
Here's a screenshot, another screen shot of Legend of Zelda,
这是一个截图 塞尔达传奇的另一个截图
inside an actual dungeon where you can see at the very top,
在一个真正的地牢里 你可以在最上面看到
there's got like a map layout.
有一个类似于地图的布局
Maps are sort of arranged in a grid.
地图在某种程度上是在网格中排列的
And you could go in a room by room, whereby each room was the entire width
你可以一个房间一个房间地进去 这样每个房间都是整个宽度
and height of the screen, looking for, solving puzzles, looking for items,
和屏幕高度 寻找 解决谜题 寻找物品
that sort of thing.
这类事情
You can see there's a monster there.
你可以看到那里有一个怪物
You have hearts at the very top right.
你们的心在最右上角
So when you take damage, hearts sort of decrement.
所以当你受到伤害时 心脏就会减少
Will see both of these, the hearts and the dungeon aspect of the game,
会看到这两个方面 游戏的心和地牢的一面
today in lecture, as well as the width and height of the room
今天的讲座 以及房间的宽度和高度
being a dungeon tile.
成为一块地牢瓷砖
And controlling an avatar.
以及控制一个化身
But this is sort of a representative screenshot of what
但这是一个有代表性的屏幕截图
the game looked like back in the day.
这场比赛看起来像是回到了过去
Some topics today that we'll be discussing in order
今天我们要讨论的一些话题
to implement sort of the foundation for what a game engine like this
来实现像这样的游戏引擎的基础
might look like are things like top down perspective.
可能看起来像是自上而下的透视法
So as you can see, in this screenshot, we're
如你所见 在这个截图中 我们
looking at Link from the very top in a bird's eye view, as opposed
在鸟瞰视图中从最高处俯瞰林肯 与之相反
to how we used to look at Mario, from the side, where
到我们过去看马里奥的方式 从侧面 在哪里
it was sort of like a side scroller.
它有点像侧滚轴
Here we're actually looking at things from the top down.
在这里 我们实际上是自上而下地看事情
So we have a view of the room in a sort of a different perspective.
所以我们以一种不同的视角来看待这个房间
There's not really a z axis, technically speaking.
从技术上讲 这并不是一个真正的z轴
But there sort of is.
但在某种程度上是有的
You can implement things like gravity in a game engine like this
您可以在游戏引擎中实现像重力这样的东西 如下所示
by jumping over holes and things like that.
通过跳跃洞穴之类的方式
But there's no gravity like there was in Super Mario,
但没有像《超级马里奥》那样的重力
where you walk left to right, you jump over gaps,
当你从左向右走的时候 你会跳过缝隙
and it's very easy to see in that sense.
从这个意义上来说 这是很容易看到的
We'll be talking about infinite dungeon generation.
我们将谈论无限的地牢世代
So in the context of today's example, we'll
因此 在今天的例子中 我们将
see how we can go about implementing a dungeon that sort of you
看看我们如何着手实施一个像你这样的地牢
can go through forever and ever, and how to sort of model that
可以永远持续下去 以及如何对其进行建模
and make it look as if you're traveling through a dungeon over and over again.
让它看起来就像你一遍又一遍地穿过地牢
And going through different screens in different rooms that are all different.
在不同的房间里通过不同的屏幕 这些房间都是不同的
But in reality, we'll see it's actually just an illusion like we've
但在现实中 我们会看到它实际上只是一个错觉 就像我们
seen before in prior lectures.
在以前的课程中见过
Well talk about hitboxes and hurtboxes, and what
我们来谈谈打击手和伤兵手 还有什么？
the difference is between the two.
两者之间的区别在于
Hitboxes being rectangles on the screen that inflict damage
希特盒是屏幕上的矩形 造成伤害
upon other entities in your game world, and hurtboxes
在您的游戏世界中的其他实体上 以及伤害盒
sort of being the rectangle that models where your player,
某种程度上是一个矩形 用来模拟你的玩家
or where an entity in the game can be hurt by other hit boxes.
或者游戏中的实体可能被其他命中框伤害的地方
Well look at events.
好的 看看这些事件
So events are a way of broadcasting some key message that tells
因此 事件是一种传播一些关键信息的方式 这些信息告诉
the game world oh this thing happened.
游戏世界哦 这件事发生了
And let me register a function to call when that event is processed.
并让我注册一个函数 以便在处理该事件时调用
So on some event, dispatch an event, and then
因此 在某些事件上 调度一个事件 然后
upon that event being received by whatever is listening for it,
在该事件被监听它的任何东西接收时
perform this chunk of code.
执行这段代码
It allows you to sort of decouple aspects of your game
它允许您在某种程度上分离游戏的各个方面
engine a little bit, and makes for a little bit more readable code.
对引擎进行了一点改进 并使代码更具可读性
And allows you to do some interesting things with achievements,
并允许你用成就做一些有趣的事情
for example, where you don't necessarily want to pull every single frame.
例如 您不一定要拉动每一帧
Oh, did I do this sort of arbitrary list of things this frame?
哦 我在这个框架里做了这种武断的事情清单吗？
Rather, you can just process all of that with an event,
相反 你可以通过一个事件来处理所有这些事情
and have a listener and a function that every time you broadcast pick up coin,
有一个监听器和一个功能 每次你播放捡硬币的时候
maybe I have an achievement that's like oh,
也许我的成就就像是
how I picked up 50 coins in this level.
我是如何在这个关卡里捡到50枚硬币的
Your achievement callback function in your event can then look for that,
然后 您的事件中的成就回调函数可以查找它
and in your game loop, you don't have to say every frame,
在你的游戏循环中 你不必说每一帧
if a player has 850 coins, and you sort of
如果一名玩家有850枚硬币 你可以说
take out bloat that would exist in your sort of overall game loop that way.
通过这种方式去掉你整个游戏循环中可能存在的臃肿
And we'll see an example of how we use that in today's lecture.
在今天的课程中 我们将看到一个如何使用它的例子
We'll look at screen scrolling.
我们将查看屏幕滚动
So a very iconic aspect of Legend of Zelda
所以《塞尔达传奇》的一个非常标志性的方面
is when you're going from one screen to another,
就是当你从一个屏幕转到另一个屏幕时
there is a sort of transition period as one screen loads and the other screen
当一个屏幕加载而另一个屏幕加载时 会有一种过渡期
goes away.
就会消失
In hardware, in the NES, this was sort of the only way
在硬件上 在NES中 这是唯一的方法
you could actually render more than a screen width of tiles.
您实际上可以渲染超过一个屏幕宽度的瓷砖
You actually had to dynamically load in tiles and sort
实际上 您必须动态加载切片并进行排序
of overwrite tiles that existed before that in memory.
覆盖在此之前存在于内存中的磁贴
But today, we'll see how we can sort of create
但今天 我们将看看如何创造出
the illusion of doing that by just drawing a room
只要画一间房间就能做到这一点的错觉
and then having our main room, and then just sort of tweening over,
然后有了我们的主房间 然后就像是补丁一样
and then setting everything back to the origin at 0.0.
然后将所有内容设置回原点为0.0
And it makes it look as if we're moving back and forth between all
这让我们看起来就像是在
these rooms, when in reality all we're doing is just doing a shift,
这些房间 而实际上我们所做的只是换班
and then putting everything back to 0.0.
然后把一切都恢复到0.0
So I'll illustrate that on the screen, if I can.
所以 如果可以的话 我会在屏幕上说明这一点
And one of the last things we'll look at is data driven design.
我们最后要讨论的一件事是数据驱动设计
In the context of a lot of types of games, particularly RPGs and action
在许多类型的游戏的背景下 特别是RPG和动作
games, it's often very valuable to be able to model all of your items,
在游戏中 能够为你所有的物品建模通常是非常有价值的
entities, sort of abilities, anything you really
实体 某种能力 任何你真正想要的东西
can, as data rather than logic, in order to make it easier for you to write one.
可以 作为数据而不是逻辑 为了让你更容易写一个
And two, for you to sort of allocate the design aspect of your game
第二 你可以分配你游戏的设计方面
to other people, not just programmers.
给其他人 而不仅仅是程序员
And have an engine that's very versatile.
并有一个非常通用的发动机
And model and we'll take a look at how we implement
和模型 我们将看看我们是如何实现
sort of a foundation for that later on.
这在某种程度上为以后的研究奠定了基础
But first I'd like to illustrate a demo for today's lecture,
但首先 我想为今天的课程演示一个演示
a sort of implementation of Legend of Zelda.
这是塞尔达传奇的一种实现
Is there anybody that would like to come up and sort of demo this today
今天有没有人愿意来演示一下这个
in class?
在课堂上？
Awesome.
太棒了
Thank you so much.
非常感谢
So whenever you're ready, go ahead and press the Return key there.
所以 只要你准备好了 就继续按那里的Return键
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
And so we see on the screen, Legend of 50, which is our Legend of Zelda
所以我们在屏幕上看到 50岁的传奇 这是我们的塞尔达传奇
you rip off.
你敲竹杠
So you press Enter.
因此 您按Enter键
You go into, this is the play state of the game.
你进入 这就是游戏的发挥状态
So you control an avatar.
所以你控制了一个化身
You can walk around.
你可以四处走走
He can interact with switches, as we saw here.
他可以与开关互动 就像我们在这里看到的那样
When he presses a switch, the doors open.
当他按下开关时 门就会打开
And once the doors are open, you can walk through them
一旦门打开了 你就可以走进去了
and it does, as I alluded to before, it transitions the screen, one
而且 正如我之前提到的 它将屏幕转换为
entire screen height or width, depending on the direction, up above and below.
整个屏幕的高度或宽度取决于向上和向下的方向
We see here now where we're pressing spacebar to actually swing our sword.
我们现在看到 我们按空格键实际上是在挥舞我们的剑
It's destroying the entities in the game space.
它正在摧毁游戏空间中的实体
So there's a hitbox triggering when you press the space bar that collides
所以当你按下碰撞的空格键时会触发Hitbox
with other entities in the game world.
与游戏世界中的其他实体
If that hitbox hits their hurtbox, then they are flagged as dead,
如果希特箱击中了他们的伤害箱 那么他们就会被标记为死亡
and they disappear from the game world.
他们从游戏世界中消失了
And so this goes on ad infinitum.
所以这就是无止境的
It's just an infinite dungeon.
这只是一个无尽的地牢
So he can go in-between as many floors as we want to.
这样他就可以进入我们想要的楼层之间
All we're doing is every time we go through a doorway, spawn a new room,
我们所做的就是每次我们穿过一扇门 生出一个新房间
delete the old one, and just keep going forever, and ever, and ever.
删除旧的 然后继续下去 永远
In a game like Legend of Zelda, it typically doesn't work like this.
在像塞尔达传奇这样的游戏中 它通常不会像这样工作
There is a hard set number of rooms, and they all exist in sort of a 2D array.
有固定数量的房间 它们都以一种2D阵列的形式存在
And when you generate your dungeon, you sort of
当你产生你的地牢时 你可以说
have to take into consideration things like where do I put the keys?
必须考虑到我把钥匙放在哪里之类的事情
Where do I put the boss?
我该把老板放在哪里？
Where do I put treasure?
我该把宝藏放在哪里？
That sort of thing.
这类事情
We won't get too in-depth as to how we can implement a complex algorithm like.
我们不会太深入地讨论如何实现像这样的复杂算法
But we'll touch on it a little bit, and talk about maybe some ideas
但我们会稍微谈一谈 也许会谈到一些想法
that we have.
这是我们拥有的
And then lastly, if we just-- if we want to demo--
最后 如果我们只是--如果我们想演示--
if we can see the top left, we have hearts there,
如果我们能看到左上角 我们的心就在那里
which is iconic sort of Zelda.
这是塞尔达的标志性作品
When we do take damage from an enemy, notice that we flicker a little bit.
当我们确实受到敌人的伤害时 注意到我们会有一点闪烁
So there's some rendering behavior triggering,
所以有一些渲染行为被触发
and we become invulnerable when we take damage.
当我们受到伤害时 我们就变得无懈可击
And then lastly, when we finally take the last hit,
最后 当我们终于接受最后一击的时候
we get a little game over screen, using the Zelda font.
我们在屏幕上看到一个小游戏 使用的是塞尔达字体
And that's the game in a nutshell.
简而言之 这就是游戏
We press Enter and loop back.
我们按Enter键并循环返回
So pretty simple altogether, but there's a lot of pieces
总体来说很简单 但有很多片段
here that we haven't really seen before.
在这里 我们从来没有真正看到过
So thank you very much for coming up to demo the game.
因此 非常感谢你们前来演示这款游戏
All right.
好的
So that was a demo of Legend of 50, Legend of Zelda.
这就是《50岁的传奇》、《塞尔达传奇》的演示
It has a lot of the pieces that Zelda has.
它有很多塞尔达拥有的东西
It's not as fully fleshed out, of course,
当然 它还没有完全充实起来
as a full game like Zelda, which would be monstrously large.
作为像塞尔达这样的完整游戏 这将是一个巨大的游戏
And there's a lot of things we need to factor in.
我们还需要考虑很多因素
But the foundation is there.
但基础就在那里
We have the dungeon foundation upon which we can build an actual generator,
我们有地牢的基础 我们可以在上面建造一个真正的发电机
if we wanted to.
如果我们想的话
We have entities.
我们有实体
We have hit boxes.
我们有命中率高的
We could easily model, because we have switches in the game,
我们可以很容易地建模 因为我们在游戏中有开关
we could model things like treasure chests that
我们可以对宝物箱这样的东西进行建模
open that have different states, just like the switch had different states.
打开有不同的状态 就像开关有不同的状态一样
And have different objects in our game space interact with other objects.
并让我们游戏空间中的不同对象与其他对象互动
We have a lot here, and we'll talk about all of it today.
我们在这里有很多东西 今天我们将讨论所有的东西
So here's a few screenshots just to show what we just looked at.
这里有几个截图 只是为了展示我们刚刚看到的东西
Our goal mainly is the second screen shot,
我们的目标主要是第二个截图
on the top right, which is the play state, which has
在右上角 这是播放状态 它具有
all of the little pieces we just saw.
我们刚刚看到的所有小碎片
But just to tie it all together, we do have a start state here,
但为了把这一切联系起来 我们这里确实有一个开始状态
and a Game Over state which is relevant in regard
以及一场与国家相关的博弈
to the hearts on the top left.
传到左上角的心脏
So the first thing that I'll talk about as we sort of get the engine built up
所以我要谈的第一件事是 我们把发动机组装好了
is, where do we go for getting our assets into the game?
是 我们要把我们的资产投入到游戏中去吗？
And just like in prior lectures, prior to today,
就像之前的课程一样 在今天之前
we just have a sprite sheet, like we did with Mario,
我们只有一个精灵床单 就像我们对马里奥所做的那样
where everything is laid out in a fairly even sequence of tile segments.
其中所有内容都以相当均匀的瓷砖分段顺序进行布局
In this case, the segments are 16 by 16 pixels.
在本例中 线段为16x16像素
Here, I've overlaid a grid just to show that the picture is indeed perfectly 16
在这里 我叠加了一个网格 只是为了显示图片确实是完美的16
by 16.
到16岁
And this is something that you should take into consideration.
这是你应该考虑的事情
And consciously do when you're building your game assets.
当你构建你的游戏资产时 你会有意识地这样做
Make it easy to chop up into little pieces,
让它很容易被切成小块
so you can then index into this sprite via some table of quads.
这样你就可以通过一些四边形的表格来索引这个精灵了
And then assign an ID to whatever object,
然后为任何对象分配ID
or tile you want to render to the screen.
或要渲染到屏幕上的平铺
And so we see if you look here, things like the doors,
所以我们看到 如果你看这里 像门这样的东西
they're not perfectly modeled by one tile.
它们并不是由一块瓷砖完美地塑造出来的
And so when you do have things that are larger than 16 by 16,
所以当你有大于16乘以16的东西时
it's not quite as easy as oh have an entity or an object with this frame ID,
这并不像拥有具有该帧ID实体或对象那样简单
and draw it to the screen.
并将其绘制到屏幕上
You actually need to a little bit more complicated render logic.
您实际上需要稍微复杂一点的呈现逻辑
So just offhand, if I wanted to draw a door,
所以随便说说 如果我想画一扇门
does anybody have any suggestions as to how I would model that?
有没有人对我如何建模有什么建议？
And or draw it to the screen?
或者把它画到屏幕上？
So if we have a door that's not perfectly a 16 x 16 pixel tile,
因此 如果我们的门不是16x16像素的瓷砖
offhand, what we need to do is just basically store all four
现在 我们需要做的就是存储所有四个
of those tiles in this case, or at least keep track of however many tiles
在这种情况下 这些瓷砖 或至少跟踪有多少瓷砖
your object is.
你的目标是
And then just draw them based on some offset.
然后只需根据一些偏移量绘制它们
Have an xy that represents the top left of that object.
具有表示该对象左上角的XY
Place it in the right position, and instead of drawing just one tile,
把它放在正确的位置 而不是只画一个瓷砖
we draw four tiles.
我们画了四块瓷砖
And then instead of having just one collision boss that's 16 by 16 tiles,
然后 不是只有一个16乘16瓦的碰撞凸起
you can do a couple of things.
你可以做几件事
You can either check collision on all four of these tiles,
您可以检查所有四个瓷砖上的碰撞
or at least all two of these door tiles, or model your own custom hit
或者至少是所有的两块门砖 或者是你自己定制的打印件
box that then maybe that object that represents a doorway has control of.
然后 可能代表门口的对象可以控制的框
So you can say doorway collides player, and then the doorway
所以你可以说门口撞到了玩家 然后门口
has a height and width of however many pixels it is wide by tall here.
它的高度和宽度是多少像素 它在这里是宽是高
Just this door part.
只有门的这一部分
And then, you are able to then build upon not just having one tile that
然后 您可以在不只有一块瓷砖的基础上构建
models an object or entity in your game space,
在您的游戏空间中为对象或实体建模
but now you have more artistic flexibility.
但现在你有了更多的艺术灵活性
You can do things like have doorways that are more than one pixel wide.
你可以做一些事情 比如有超过一个像素宽的门口
And sort of have a more convincing gameworld as a result of that.
因此 游戏世界变得更有说服力了
You'll see a lot of things like that in games like RPGs
你会在RPG这样的游戏中看到很多类似的东西
where you have full houses that are obviously not just one tile.
在那里 你有满座的房子 显然不仅仅是一块瓷砖
You can model things as one tile if you want to,
如果你愿意 你可以用一块瓷砖来建模
but from an artistic perspective, and from just a game engine perspective,
但从艺术的角度 从游戏引擎的角度来看
it's a little bit easier to programmatically
它以编程方式更容易一些
be able to cut up all your assets into tiles and draw them as such.
能够将你所有的资产切成瓷砖 然后这样画出来
So being able to build upon just the single sprite
所以能够在单人精灵的基础上
and be able to do multiple sprites represent
并且能够用多个精灵来表示
an object is the key to things like houses, things like big trees,
物体是房屋、大树等事物的关键
things that are just more complicated than single tiles as we see here.
比我们在这里看到的单一瓷砖更复杂的东西
The character sprite sheet is, as you can see, a little bit more complicated.
正如你所看到的 角色的精灵工作表有点复杂
So this is an example of a sprite sheet that has padding.
这是一个带有填充的精灵工作表的示例
Sometimes you will get sprite sheets that aren't neatly divided
有时你会得到没有被整齐分割的精灵床单
into even segments.
分成偶数段
And for good reason.
这是有充分理由的
Because sometimes you have tiles that are not perfectly
因为有时候你的瓷砖不是很完美
the width and height of whatever your game engine's tiles are.
游戏引擎的瓷砖的宽度和高度
In this case, the player is actually 20 pixels tall, and 16 pixels wide.
在这种情况下 播放器实际上是20像素高 16像素宽
And on top of that, he's got different frames of animation.
最重要的是 他有不同的动画画面
We can see here at the bottom left, he's got a sword swinging animation.
我们可以在左下角看到 他有一个挥剑的动画
The sword swing animation is actually stored in a 32 by 32 pixel frame,
挥剑动画实际上存储在32×32像素的帧中
because sometimes depending on which angle he's looking at,
因为有时取决于他看的角度
his sprite can get a little larger or smaller.
他的精灵可以变大一点 也可以变小一点
So when you have a sprite with padding, what's sort of a way
所以当你有一个带衬垫的精灵 什么是一种
that we can draw this to the screen reliably?
我们可以可靠地把这个画到屏幕上吗？
How do we take this into consideration?
我们该如何考虑这一点呢？
How would we render a screen sprite with padding?
我们将如何呈现带有填充的屏幕精灵？
So let's say this sprite here, our character swinging a sword, is in a 32
所以让我们假设这个精灵 我们的角色挥舞着一把剑 是在32
by 32 pixel box.
乘以32像素框
Right?
对吗？
This sort of box around here, this white space.
在这附近的这个盒子 这个空白空间
But he's only still maybe 16 pixels wide by 20 pixels tall.
但他仍然可能只有16个像素宽乘20个像素高
Or maybe he is some amount similar to that.
或者 也许他在某种程度上与此类似
In order to draw him to the screen, which you can look at in the code,
为了把他吸引到屏幕上 你可以在代码中看到
all we really need to do is assign that sprite an offset.
我们真正需要做的就是为那个精灵分配一个偏移量
Just say, OK, this sprite's offset x and offset
只要说 好的 这个精灵的偏移量x和偏移量
y are some value that basically lets us draw the sprite
Y是一些值 基本上可以让我们绘制精灵
to a negative x and a negative y value.
为负的x和负的y值
And that'll shift the sprite up, such that it aligns perfectly
这将使精灵向上移动 使其完美地对齐
with wherever his xy are.
无论他的XY在哪里
And you can take a look at the code to see exactly how that works.
您可以查看代码以了解它到底是如何工作的
Lastly the actual entities for our game world are different creatures.
最后 我们游戏世界的实际实体是不同的生物
And this is a sprite sheet-- this is a more ideal sprite where everything
这是一张精灵图--这是一张更理想的精灵图
is 16 by 16 pixels wide and tall.
是16x16像素宽和高
And all we really did here was just divide the sprite sheet
我们在这里真正做的就是分好精灵床单
using the regular utility function generate quads by 16 16.
使用常规实用函数生成16个16的四边形
We don't have to worry about separate widths and heights for everything,
我们不必担心所有东西都有不同的宽度和高度
and we can create animations very simply because of this.
正因为如此 我们才能非常简单地制作动画
As a side note, something that I like to do, when I'm parsing
顺便说一句 当我在解析时 我喜欢做的事情
or when I'm piecing apart a sprite sheet that's got a lot of individual frames,
或者当我拼接一张有很多单独框架的精灵纸时
particularly if I'm creating animations, or I just
尤其是在我创作动画的时候 或者我只是
need to know for a tile, a particular tile to draw to the screen.
需要知道对于一个瓷砖 一个特定的瓷砖要画到屏幕上
It's kind of a pain to manually look through each and every tile, one
手动查看每一块瓷砖是一种痛苦
by one.
差一分
And say OK, this is one but OK.
然后说好的 这是一个 但是好的
But if I want to find out which one the slime is,
但如果我想找出粘液是哪一种
I got a count, OK how many pixels wide does this?
我数了一下 好的 这个有多少像素宽？
OK, and then it's times 4, it's 12.
好的 然后是4乘以12
And then it's on the fifth row, so 12 times 4 plus 1 will give me, OK.
然后它在第五排 所以12乘以4加1会得到 好的
So it's at index 49.
所以它的指数是49
So I've spent a non-trivial amount of time sort of hand
所以我花了相当多的时间
calculating what all these do.
计算所有这些都做了什么
I wrote a simple Python script that will just go over a file,
我编写了一个简单的Python脚本 它只会遍历一个文件
and just add a digit to each individual quad,
只需在每个单独的四元组中添加一个数字
to just show you at a glance what each sprite is.
让你一目了然地看到每个精灵是什么
And this is including the distro, so you can see what it looks like.
这包括发行版 所以你可以看到它是什么样子的
Saves a lot of time.
节省了很多时间
And I recommend trying, when you're sort of working with assets
我建议尝试一下 当你在处理资产的时候
and you find yourself doing something that takes a long time,
你发现自己在做一件需要很长时间的事情
and it's sort of tedious and mechanical, maybe
这可能有点繁琐和机械
try to find a way to sort of automate that, or at least
试着找到一种自动化的方法 或者至少
make it easier to do things at a glance.
让事情变得更容易一目了然
In this case, just simply imposing a numerical grid solves that problem.
在这种情况下 只需简单地施加一个数字网格就可以解决这个问题
I don't have to spend a significant amount of time
我不需要花很多时间
figuring out which frames of animation the ghost facing left is.
找出幽灵面向左侧的动画的哪一帧
I know instantly it's 67, 68 and 69, and allows me to just crank things
我立刻就知道它是67、68和69 这让我可以把事情搞砸
up that much faster.
升得快得多
So the first thing we'll take a look at is sort of top down perspective.
所以我们首先要看的是一种自上而下的视角
And we mostly talked about this before, earlier.
我们之前主要讨论过这个问题 早些时候
But all it really is is a tile map, which we've seen before.
但它实际上只是一张我们以前见过的瓷砖地图
The only difference is now, instead of looking at things from the side,
唯一的不同是 现在不是从侧面看事情
we're just looking at things from up above.
我们只是从上面看事情
So what's probably the most obvious consideration
那么最明显的考虑可能是什么呢？
when designing a top down perspective versus a sort of side scrolling
在设计自上而下的透视图而不是侧边滚动时
point of view?
观点是什么？
Looking at particularly at how the tiles are drawn?
特别关注瓷砖是如何绘制的？
What stands out?
最突出的是什么？
So the thing that stands out to me is that we
所以对我来说最突出的是我们
have things like shadows on walls here.
这里的墙壁上有影子之类的东西
We have also corners, and things altogether
我们也有角落 和所有的东西
are skewed such that they are almost like rotated slightly as if they're
是倾斜的 以至于它们几乎像是稍微旋转了一下 就好像它们
simulating an angle of rotation relative to the camera facing from up above.
模拟相对于相机从上方朝上的旋转角度
You can see this on the player, for example.
例如 你可以在播放器上看到这一点
It looks like you're looking at him from backwards and up.
看起来你是在上下打量他
When you're modeling your assets that way, it's more convincing.
当你以这种方式为你的资产建模时 它更有说服力
And Zelda has always done this, to make your assets look
泽尔达总是这样做 让你的资产看起来
as if they are slightly tilted, and that you're looking up above.
就好像它们略微倾斜 你抬头看着上面
So when you're designing a top down game, just
所以当你设计一个自上而下的游戏时 只要
for convincing the sake of being more convincing, try and emulate that.
为了令人信服 为了更有说服力 试着效仿一下
The entities here, like the skeleton, and such,
这里的实体 比如骨架 等等
are a little bit more straight on.
更直截了当一点
The bats and slimes and whatnot, even though they still
蝙蝠和泥巴之类的东西 尽管他们仍然
have a little bit of that appearance.
有一点那样的外表
Like the spider it sort of looks as if it's from the top back.
就像蜘蛛一样 它看起来有点像是从上到后的
But modeling your assets from a top down perspective, mainly the thing.
但从自上而下的角度对你的资产进行建模 主要是这件事
Pay attention to shadows and highlights, which
注意阴影和高光 它们
adds a lot in terms of convincing us that we're in this room with lighting.
增加了很多方面 让我们相信我们是在这个有灯光的房间里
And also make sure that you're doing things like corners and stuff
还要确保你做的事情像是拐角之类的
and making, it look as if things are slightly skewed rotation wise.
而且 它看起来似乎是稍微倾斜的旋转方向
The first thing that we're going to look at in terms of the code in the distro
我们要看的第一件事是发行版中的代码
is Dungeon Generation.
就是地牢一代
So in Legend of Zelda, dungeons are fixed.
所以在塞尔达传说中 地下城是固定的
They're completely set in advance by the designers.
它们完全是设计师事先设定的
And in most games, this is actually the case.
在大多数游戏中 实际情况就是这样
In our example, and in a couple of other examples,
在我们的例子中 以及其他几个例子中
a primary example of them being that I can think of,
其中一个主要的例子是我能想到的
that I have in the slides, a famous game called The Binding of Isaac,
我在幻灯片中看到了一个著名的游戏 叫做《艾萨克的装订》
dungeons can also be generated.
也可以生成地下城
So what's the sort of like the main unit of a dungeon?
那么 地下城的主单元是什么样的呢？
At least in the context of Legend of Zelda?
至少在《塞尔达传奇》的背景下是这样？
If you had to distill what comprises a dungeon,
如果你必须提炼出地下城的组成成分
what's the most fundamental unit?
最基本的单位是什么？
Tony.
托尼
A room.
一个房间
Yes.
是
So we can almost look at this, if we picture it in terms of a 2D array,
所以我们几乎可以看到这一点 如果我们用2D阵列来描述它
right?
对吗？
We have, assuming that this is like index 1.1
我们有 假设这类似于指数1.1
in Lua, 0.0 in other languages, going left to right, top to bottom.
在Lua中是0.0 在其他语言中是从左到右、从上到下
Basically we have on or off, relative to each of these.
基本上 我们有开或关 相对于每一个
Off, on, off, off, off.
关 开 关
Each of the indexes in this 2D array holds a room.
这个2D数组中的每个索引都有一个空间
And so the room has connections implicitly between the other rooms.
因此 这个房间在其他房间之间有隐含的联系
If you wanted to go, let's say, from this room here to the room
如果你想去 比方说 从这个房间到这个房间
up above it, what's the offset, in terms of the 2D array?
在它上面 就2D数组而言 偏移量是多少？
How are we going from this room up to this room?
我们要怎么从这个房间走到这个房间？
So we're just going up a y level, right?
所以我们只是上升了一级 对吗？
So this is x level 3, y level 3.
这是x级3 y级3
If we wanted to go up to the next room, we need to load in.
如果我们想上到隔壁房间 我们需要上车
If we're doing it the Zelda way, right?
如果我们用泽尔达的方式来做 对吗？
And we're just going--
我们只是要去--
we're doing a transition between one room
我们在一个房间和一个房间之间做过渡
to another, what we need to do is load in the room at this room,
对另一个人来说 我们需要做的就是在这个房间里装东西
minus one on the y, and then perform the transition.
在y上减去1 然后执行转换
And then set that to the current room, such
然后将其设置为当前房间 例如
that now we know we're at y level 2, x level 3.
现在我们知道我们处于y水平2 x水平3
That's our dungeon.
那是我们的地牢
In the context of 2D dungeons in The Legend of Zelda,
在塞尔达传说中的2D地下城的背景下
that's as simple as it really is.
这就像它的实际情况一样简单
You have a 2D grid of dungeon rooms.
你有一个由地牢房间组成的2D网格
Each room has its own collection of entities and objects
每个房间都有自己的实体和对象集合
and connections to other rooms.
以及与其他房间的联系
But really, all you do to fill a dungeon is fill an array in a smart way
但实际上 填充地牢所要做的就是以一种智能的方式填充数组
such that there is no rooms that are, for example, left by themselves.
使得不存在例如它们自己留下的房间
Notice that every room in the dungeon has at least one connection
请注意 地牢中的每个房间都至少有一个连接
to another room.
去另一个房间
And that when you're maybe doing your algorithm
当你在做你的算法时
to create a convincing dungeon, let's say this room here has
为了创造一个令人信服的地下城 让我们假设这里的这个房间有
a door on the right, that has a lock.
右边有一扇门 门上有锁
Right?
对吗？
We want to make sure that the key isn't in that room.
我们要确保钥匙不在那个房间里
Because if it is, we're never going to be
因为如果是的话 我们永远都不会是
able to get to it, assuming that we come from another direction.
能够到达它 假设我们来自另一个方向
So when you're designing dungeons procedurally,
所以当你按程序设计地牢时
you want to take these sort of things into consideration.
你想把这些事情都考虑进去
And then for example, the boss room.
然后 例如 老板的房间
Let's say this is the boss room, the boss room
假设这是老板的房间 老板的房间
should have maybe a boss key, or something like that.
应该有一把老板的钥匙之类的
But the boss key should not be, obviously, in that room.
但显然 老板的钥匙不应该在那个房间里
It should be somewhere maybe where there's a couple of rooms before it
它应该在某个地方 也许前面还有几个房间
that have a lock or a key, so that you know there's some sort of challenge
有一把锁或一把钥匙 这样你就知道有某种挑战
involved in your dungeon.
卷入了你的地牢
It's not just random as we've done before.
这不是像我们以前做的那样只是随机的
There has to be a little bit of sort of conscious design on behalf
必须有一些有意识的设计来代表
of your algorithms.
你的算法
Today we're doing things completely random
今天我们做的事情完全是随机的
for illustration, just because a system like this is fairly robust and complex.
作为说明 仅仅因为像这样的系统是相当健壮和复杂的
But with some effort, you could create a simple dungeon generator just using
但只要付出一些努力 您就可以创建一个简单的地下城生成器
those mechanics.
那些机械师
Just make sure that you have locked doors.
只要确保你锁上门就行了
The locked doors can only open when you have a key.
只有当你有钥匙时 锁着的门才能打开
Make sure the key exists in a place that's accessible,
确保钥匙放在可以接近的地方
and sort of create a chain of a control flow.
并在某种程度上创建了一个控制流的链
Model maybe via graph of some kind that represents your dungeon,
模型可以通过某种图形来表示你的地牢
and the progression thereof.
以及它的进程
So that's what a Zelda dungeon looks like.
这就是塞尔达地牢的样子
That's what a 2D dungeon in this sort of perspective looks like.
这就是2D地牢在这种视角下的样子
And it looks-- it will look similar to this in other game engines.
而且它看起来--它看起来会和其他游戏引擎中的类似
It doesn't necessarily have to be perfectly modeled
它不一定要被完美地建模
as a screen width, screen height room going into another screen width, screen
作为一个屏幕宽度 屏幕高度空间变成另一个屏幕宽度 屏幕
wide room.
房间很宽敞
You can have arbitrarily complex rooms that have arbitrarily complex sizes
您可以拥有任意复杂的房间 这些房间的大小可以任意复杂
and shapes.
和形状
But you still need to make sure that the connections going out of the rooms,
但你仍然需要确保房间外的连接
like if you can still model left, right, up, down, if you want to.
如果你还能做左、右、上、下的模型 如果你想的话
You can model arbitrary numbers of connections between rooms.
您可以对房间之间的任意数量的连接进行建模
Just make sure that you have puzzles that can be solved.
只要确保你有可以解决的谜题
That's the main sort of obstacle in generating your dungeons.
这是产生你的地下城的主要障碍
Here's a game that I really like that uses the old Legend of Zelda formula
这是一款我非常喜欢的游戏 它使用了塞尔达传奇的古老公式
to very good effect now.
现在效果非常好
It's called The Binding of Isaac.
这叫做《以撒的捆绑》
Notice already we can instantly see that it's top-down perspective.
请注意 我们已经可以立即看到它是自上而下的透视图
It's the entire width and height of the room is the dungeon of--
整个房间的宽度和高度都是--
the entire width and height of the screen is the dungeon room.
整个屏幕的宽度和高度都是地下城的房间
You have a map up here that shows you, OK, I'm in this room right here.
这里有一张地图 上面显示 好的 我就在这个房间里
I can go up, I can go left.
我可以上去 我可以往左走
I can go right, I can go down.
我可以向右走 我可以往下走
This room up here with the yellow crown, that's
上面这个黄色皇冠的房间 那是
going to be locked behind some door with a key.
会被锁在某个门后面 拿着钥匙
So we need to have keys that spawn in any of these rooms that
所以我们需要有在这些房间里产生的钥匙
are just blindly accessible.
只是盲目地接近而已
And Isaac does things a little bit differently also
艾萨克做事情的方式也有点不同
in that it generates keys and bombs randomly,
因为它随机生成密钥和炸弹
so that you can actually get--
这样你就可以真正得到--
you don't necessarily have to plant your keys in very specific locations,
你不一定要把钥匙放在非常特定的位置
if your algorithm is sufficiently accommodating and complex enough.
如果您的算法足够灵活和足够复杂
You can just at, the end of every room, have a chance to spawn a key randomly.
你可以在每个房间的尽头 有机会随机产生一把钥匙
And if you're lucky, or if you're not lucky, and assuming
如果你幸运 或者如果你不幸运 假设
that the end of the dungeon doesn't exist behind your locked doors.
地牢的尽头并不存在于你锁着的门后面
You have the opportunity to stall and lock those doors, or not.
你有机会拖延并锁上那些门 或者不
And just go on through your dungeon as needed.
并在需要的时候穿过你的地牢
In this case, they don't lock the boss doors.
在这种情况下 他们不会锁上老板的门
So you can go through the boss door regardless of whether you have a key.
这样 无论你有没有钥匙 你都可以通过老板的门
So they've accommodated for this purely random approach,
所以他们已经适应了这种纯粹随机的方法
and that just goes to illustrate how you can still take randomisation
这正好说明了你如何仍然可以采取随机化
using very complex principles, and produce games
使用非常复杂的原理 并制作游戏
that are extremely addicting and fun.
非常令人上瘾和有趣的东西
And you don't necessarily need to be super elaborate.
而且你也不一定要非常详细
The first thing, OK.
第一件事 好的
So hitboxes and hurtboxes will be the next topic.
因此 热门话题和伤害性话题将成为下一个话题
So I want to touch on, in the code, how we sort of do dungeon
所以 我想在代码中谈一谈 我们是如何在地下城
generation in the game engine here.
这是游戏引擎中的一代
So I'm going to open up--
所以我要敞开心扉
there's a few files.
有几份文件
So doorway, notice in the source distro, there's a World folder.
请注意 在源代码发行版中 有一个World文件夹
We've sort of categorized all of the files that
我们已经对所有的文件进行了分类
have to do with world generation within that World folder.
与那个World文件夹中的世界一代有关
We have a doorway file, we have a dungeon file, and we have a room file.
我们有一份门口档案 一份地牢档案 还有一份房间档案
So the dungeon file models the dungeon.
因此 地牢文件对地牢进行了建模
All of the rooms that form our dungeon, just as a very high, level top
所有形成我们地牢的房间 就像一个非常高的 水平的顶层
level, data structure.
级别、数据结构
It's actually very simple.
其实很简单
The room is, as we saw before, the individual unit of the dungeon.
正如我们之前看到的 这个房间是地牢的个体单位
So a dungeon is effectively like a table of rooms.
因此 地牢实际上就像一张房间的桌子
And then it holds the code for how we can transition between them.
然后它保存着我们如何在它们之间转换的代码
But that's sort of how we can think about it.
但这在某种程度上是我们可以思考的
When you a game level in general, in this case dungeon
当你的游戏水平一般时 在这种情况下是地下城
is sort of our game level.
在某种程度上是我们的比赛水平
You can model the different subset aspects
您可以对不同的子集方面建模
of your level via some data structure.
通过某种数据结构来了解你的水平
In this case, we've decided to make it room.
在这种情况下 我们决定把它腾出空间
But if you have just a platform or level,
但如果你只有一个平台或关卡
maybe you have regions or zones, or anything.
也许你有区域或区域 或任何东西
Just little subsegments of your level that you can transition between.
只是你所在级别的一些小部分 你可以在它们之间过渡
It's useful to think in terms of that, because from an efficiency
从这个角度考虑是很有用的 因为从效率来看
and performance standpoint, you want to dynamically probably load
从性能的角度来看 您希望动态加载
certain levels one at a time.
特定的级别 一次一个
Certain aspects, certain components, sub areas of your level, one at a time,
某些方面 某些部分 你所在水平的子领域 一次一个
rather than just the entire level at once,
而不是一次只有整个级别
because depending on how sufficiently complex and large your level is,
因为这取决于你的关卡有多复杂和多大
you can get to exercising your computer's memory constraints.
您可以开始练习您的计算机的内存限制
So don't want to do that.
所以我不想这么做
So in this case, our algorithm is we have a dungeon, we have rooms.
所以在这种情况下 我们的算法是我们有一个地牢 我们有房间
We have one active room that's only visible at one time that's
我们有一个活动房间 只能在同一时间看到 那是
loaded in memory.
加载到内存中
And then whenever we transition between rooms,
然后每当我们在不同房间之间转换时
we want to have another room that gets temporarily loaded.
我们想要另一间临时入住的房间
So let's look at the dungeon class here.
那么让我们来看看这里的地下城班级
Dungeon.lua.
地下城 卢亚
So 14 self-taught rooms, empty table.
所以14间自学的房间 空着桌子
We're going to fill that with rooms, just room objects.
我们要在里面放满房间 就是房间里的东西
Self.currentroom.
自助室
Room, and we're going to pass it in the player.
房间 我们要把它传给球员
So that the player has access to all the entities and objects therein,
从而玩家可以访问其中的所有实体和对象
and can do things like collision detection, which is very important.
可以做碰撞检测之类的事情 这是非常重要的
And also so that the entities in the room can look at the player
也是为了让房间里的实体可以看到玩家
and then decide what they want to do with their AI, which
然后决定他们想要对他们的人工智能做什么
you can model arbitrarily complex.
您可以对任意复杂的模型进行建模
The whole init function of room.lua is going, we're going to show it here.
Room.lua的整个初始化函数都在运行 我们将在这里展示它
So in room.lua, in that same world folder,
所以在room.lua中 在同一个World文件夹中
we've instantiated the dungeon at a high level.
我们已经在高级别实例化了地牢
We know the dungeons, it's basically a table of rooms.
我们知道地牢 它基本上是一张桌子的房间
So what's a room look like?
那么房间是什么样子的呢？
Well a room, as we saw before, what are the pieces
嗯 一个房间 就像我们以前看到的 有哪些部分
that a room needs in order to function?
一个房间需要什么才能发挥作用？
What does the room have to sort of keep control of?
在某种程度上 房间需要控制什么？
AUDIENCE: Doors.
观众：门
COLTON OGDEN: Doors.
科尔顿·奥格登：门
Anything else?
还要别的吗？
So doors it has to keep track of, right?
所以它必须跟踪门 对吗？
Because when we touch a door, we should transition to the next room.
因为当我们触摸一扇门时 我们应该过渡到另一个房间
It should keep track of the player.
它应该跟踪玩家
So the player can update.
这样玩家就可以更新了
It should keep track of objects in the room like switches,
它应该跟踪房间里的物体 比如开关
as we saw in the example, such that they can update those.
正如我们在示例中看到的 这样他们就可以更新那些
And see has the player stepped on the switch?
看看这位选手踩到开关了吗？
If he has, open the doors.
如果他有 就把门打开
And then entities, right?
然后是实体 对吗？
It should keep track of all of the creatures in the room
它应该跟踪房间里的所有生物
so that they can update, they can interact with each other.
这样他们就可以更新 他们可以相互互动
The player can hit them, or they can hit the player.
球员可以打他们 或者他们可以打球员
And you can model whatever interactions you want to.
您可以对任何您想要的交互进行建模
So we can see here.
所以我们可以在这里看到
Oh, and another thing too.
哦 还有一件事
Probably one of the more important visual aspects of it,
可能是它更重要的视觉方面之一
we need to also have a set of tiles that model what the room looks like.
我们还需要一套瓷砖来模拟房间的样子
It's a container.
这是一个集装箱
So we're going to draw, we have a corner, a corner, a corner, a corner.
所以我们要画 我们有一个角 一个角
Walls on the sides.
两边都是墙
Walls on the top and bottom.
顶部和底部的墙
And then a floor.
然后是一层楼
And so we need to obviously draw the room
所以我们显然需要画出房间
before we draw all of the other things, and update all the other things.
在我们画出所有其他的东西之前 更新所有其他的东西
So tiles, doorways, entities, and objects.
因此 瓷砖、门口、实体和对象
So we can see here.
所以我们可以在这里看到
You have tiles, soft-lit tiles against an empty table.
你有瓷砖 柔和的瓷砖靠在一张空桌子上
We have a function called Generate Walls And Floors.
我们有一个叫做生成墙和楼板的功能
Entities, empty table.
实体、空表
We have a function called Generate Entities.
我们有一个名为生成实体的函数
And then objects equals empty table.
然后对象就等于空桌了
We have a function called Generate Objects.
我们有一个名为生成对象的函数
And lastly, doorways.
最后是门口
And then here because it's not necessarily
然后是这里 因为它不一定
as complex as we need for a entire function, we just have four doorways.
就像我们需要一个完整的功能一样复杂 我们只有四个门
And this is static.
这是静态的
I've chosen in this example to have all the doorways always
在本例中 我选择始终保留所有的门口
be in the same place, and sort of behave in the same way.
处于相同的位置 并以相同的方式行事
But you could create a more complex system, whereby especially
但您可以创建一个更复杂的系统 特别是
if you have an algorithm that generates a dungeon dynamically,
如果你有一个动态生成地牢的算法
and maybe your rooms aren't necessarily hard set.
也许你的房间不一定是硬性的
Maybe you have a broom, right?
也许你有一把扫帚 对吧？
If we go back to our slides earlier.
如果我们早点回到我们的幻灯片
And let's say we're looking at this room right here in the very center.
让我们假设我们看的是这个房间 就在这个最中间的地方
We can see it has a doorway on the left, a doorway up top,
我们可以看到它的左边有一个门 上面有一个门
and a doorway to the right.
右手边还有一扇门
But there's no doorway on the bottom.
但它的底部没有通道
And that looks like an arbitrary design decision on behalf of the designers.
这看起来像是代表设计师的一个武断的设计决定
But if we look at this room up top here, we
但如果我们看看上面的这个房间 我们
can see that it sort of behaves in the same way.
可以看到它在某种程度上是以同样的方式运行的
There's a doorway going into this room to the left.
左边有一扇门通往这个房间
There's doorway going to this room down below.
下面有一个通往这个房间的门道
But it doesn't have a doorway up top and a doorway on the right,
但上面没有门 右边也没有门
because there are no rooms going between that room and those directions.
因为那个房间和那些方向之间没有房间
So when you have a 2D array of dungeon rooms,
所以当你有一个二维地牢房间阵列时
and you want to model your doorways, it can be as simple
你想要为你的门口建模 它可以很简单
as is there room in that direction?
那么 那个方向还有空间吗？
If there is, and you will have your data structures sort of
如果有 您将拥有您的数据结构
laid out in advance before you generate these doorways, if it does not exist,
在生成这些门口之前预先布置好 如果它不存在
don't make a door.
不要做一扇门
If it does exist, make a door.
如果它确实存在 就做一扇门
And then make sure that when you transition
然后确保当你过渡的时候
between from the right to the left, or from the bottom to the top,
从右到左 或者从下到上
that you go to the correct rooms at the correct indices in your 2D room array.
您可以在2D房间阵列中以正确的索引进入正确的房间
Does that make sense?
这说得通吗？
Anybody have any questions so far as to like how this works at a high level?
到目前为止 有没有人有什么问题想知道这是如何在高层运作的？
OK?
好的?
Awesome.
太棒了
So these doorways here are all because of this dungeon
所以这里的这些门道都是因为这座地牢
is completely random, and every time it always has doorways going top, bottom,
是完全随机的 每次它总是有通向顶部和底部的门
left and right.
左手和右手
We're always just going to put four doorways,
我们总是要放四扇门
going top, bottom, left and right.
从上 下 左 右
Note that they take a string denoting which
请注意 它们接受一个字符串 表示
direction they are, and this will become important
它们是方向 这将变得重要
later on in the doorway class, which we see here
稍后在Doorway课程中 我们在这里看到
is modeled as a separate class.
被建模为单独的类
False here just means is the door open?
这里的FALSE只是意味着门是开着的吗？
So by default, we're going to close the door.
因此 默认情况下 我们将关闭门
And then self, so that we have access to the room from the doorway.
然后是自己 这样我们就可以从门口进入房间
The room should have a reference to the player,
房间里应该有球员的名字
so that it can model interactions between the entities and the player,
这样它就可以对实体和玩家之间的交互进行建模
as well as the objects and the player.
以及物品和球员
Notice that it has a render offset.
请注意 它具有渲染偏移
So if we look at the game here, the tiles
所以如果我们看看这个游戏 瓷砖
don't completely match up to the width and height of the screen.
不要与屏幕的宽度和高度完全匹配
And that's mainly a function of the virtual height
这主要是虚拟高度的函数
not mapping perfectly to 16 tiles, divided evenly by 16 tiles.
没有完美地映射到16个瓷砖 由16个瓷砖均匀划分
So what I've done is I've made the dungeon a little bit smaller.
所以我所做的就是把地牢变小了一点
And also the fact that the doorways take up a couple of extra tiles of padding
还有一个事实是 门口占据了几块额外的衬垫
on their sides, it's like sort of blank space up here.
在他们的一侧 这里就像是一片空白
We've shifted everything inwards a little bit.
我们已经将所有东西都稍微向内移动了一点
We've made the dungeon two tiles smaller width and height wise than the screen.
我们已经把地牢做了两块 宽度和高度都比屏幕小
And then we've just rendered offset by a certain amount
然后我们呈现了一定数量的偏移量
such that it's completely centered.
使其完全居中
We calculate how much padding exists between the fully rendered dungeon
我们计算在完全渲染的地下城之间存在多少填充
and whatever blank space is left, and just shift by half of that amount,
不管剩下什么空格 只要移动一半就行了
and that's our render offset.
这是我们的渲染偏移量
So that's why render offset is important in this case.
因此 这就是渲染偏移在这种情况下很重要的原因
When you're trying to center anything, you typically
当你试图将任何东西放在中心时 你通常会
do it just by calculating an offset.
只需计算一个偏移量即可
Calculate the width and height of whatever you're trying to draw,
计算你想要画的任何东西的宽度和高度
calculate whatever your width and height of your screen is minus that,
计算屏幕的宽度和高度减去它
divide it by 2, that's your render offset.
将其除以2 这就是渲染偏移
And then these two fields here are interesting. self.adjacentoffsetX,
这里的这两个领域很有趣 自邻接偏移X
self.adjectentoffsetY.
Self.adjectoffsetY
Does anybody have a guess as to what this is used for?
有没有人猜到这是用来做什么的？
Yeah.
嗯
Drawing itself when it's the adjacent room.
当它在隔壁房间的时候画自己
Yes, exactly.
是的 没错
So drawing itself when it's the adjacent room.
所以当它在隔壁房间的时候画自己
So when you load the next room, you're going
所以当你装上下一个房间的时候 你要
to instantiate a room just like this.
实例化一个房间 就像这样
But by default it's going to draw at 0.0.
但默认情况下 它将绘制为0.0
However, if we want that room to draw not right where we are.
然而 如果我们想要那个房间画在我们不合适的地方
Obviously, if we're in the current room, we
显然 如果我们在现在的房间里 我们
don't want the next room drawing right on top
我不想让隔壁的房间画在最上面
of where we are, because then it's just going to layer right
我们所处的位置 因为那样它就会层次分明
on top of the room we're in.
在我们所在的房间顶端
And we want to draw it--
我们想把它画出来--
if we're going to the right, we want to draw a screen width to the right.
如果我们要向右转 则需要向右绘制屏幕宽度
If we're drawing it to the left, we want to draw it a screen width to the left.
如果我们将其绘制到左侧 我们希望将其绘制为左侧的屏幕宽度
And same thing on the y-axis.
在y轴上也是一样的
A screen height above, or below it.
上方或下方的屏幕高度
So adjacentoffsetX or y, we just add to when we draw the room.
所以相邻的偏移量X或y 我们在画房间的时候加进去就行了
And that'll have the effect of rendering it separately from the room
这将产生与房间分开渲染的效果
that we're currently in.
我们目前所处的位置
I can try and draw an illustration here.
我可以试着在这里画一个插图
So if we have our room here, this is our current room.
所以 如果我们有我们的房间 这就是我们现在的房间
So self.currentroom.
太自私了 房间里
And let's say we have a doorway here.
假设我们在这里有一扇门
Right?
对吗？
That's a doorway object, the player is here.
那是一个门口的物体 玩家在这里
He collides with that object.
他撞上了那个物体
It's going to trigger a transition to a room up above.
它会触发一个过渡到上面的房间
So what we do is we load in a new room right away.
所以我们要做的就是马上搬进一个新房间
We always have a pointer called self.nextroom.
我们总是有一个名为self.nextroom的指针
And this is all kept track of in the dungeod.lua file.
这些都记录在dungeod.lua文件中
But self.nextroom by default is going to be nil.
但在默认情况下 self.nextroom将为零
But when we transition from the current room to the next room, right?
但是当我们从现在的房间过渡到下一个房间的时候 对吗？
We should set that to something.
我们应该把它设置成某种东西
So self.currentroom is going to be the same.
因此 self.Curentroom将是相同的
But when we trigger this collision, self.nextroom,
但当我们触发这场碰撞时
this is going to be equal to just a new room.
这将只相当于一个新房间
And then we get which doorway we're in.
然后我们就知道我们在哪个门口了
We figure it out.
我们会想办法的
We figure out which direction we're moving in, technically.
从技术上讲 我们会弄清楚我们要朝哪个方向前进
And then if we're moving up, then we just pass in a--
然后如果我们往上走 我们就会通过一个--
we said it's adjacent offset y in this case, to negative screen height.
在这种情况下 我们说它与负屏幕高度的偏移量y相邻
If it's below, we set it to positive screen height.
如果它低于屏幕高度 则将其设置为正屏幕高度
If we go here, it's going to be negative screen with the adjacent x,
如果我们到这里 它将是负屏 与相邻的x
will be negative screen width.
将为负屏宽
And then positive screen width on the x if we're moving to the right.
如果我们向右移动 那么x上的正屏幕宽度
And so this sort of adjacent we could see, if do xy,
所以我们可以看到这种相邻的 如果是XY
it will be that's basically the adjacent offset.
这基本上就是相邻的偏移量
And so we end up when we draw our transition going from bottom to
最后我们画出了从底部到
up in this case, we just tween the camera to this value.
在这种情况下 我们只是补间相机到这个值
So we have a camera, right?
我们有摄像头 对吧？
This is our camera.
这是我们的相机
And it's going to be looking here by default. So camera x and camera y,
默认情况下它会看这里 摄像机x和摄像机y
those are values in our code as well.
这些也是我们代码中的价值观
When we trigger this collision on the doorway,
当我们在门口触发碰撞时
and we have current room here, which is at 0.0,
这里有当前的空间 它是0.0
and then we have this room here, which is at 0 plus our adjacent
这里有一个房间 它的位置是0加上相邻的
offset y, which is negative screen height.
偏移y 这是负的屏幕高度
So it has the effect of making it negative screen height on the y.
所以它的作用是使屏幕高度在y轴上为负
Our camera x recall love.graphics.Translate is our camera.
我们的相机x回忆爱 图形 翻译是我们的相机
So all we do is we just tween that.
所以我们要做的就是在两者之间
We say, OK.
我们说 好的
Here's our Cam x is going to be here.
这是我们的X号摄像机会在这里.
And Cam y, it's getting a little bit messy.
小卡 有点乱了
I apologize.
我道歉
But our camera x and y are here.
但是我们的x和y摄像头在这里
And then over time, we're going to tween that up into the next rooms
随着时间的推移 我们会把它放到下一个房间
x and y, which is a just x plus adjacent offset x, y plus adjacent offset y.
x和y 即x加上相邻偏移x y加上相邻偏移y
And then once this camera has shifted from here up to here,
一旦摄像机从这里移到这里
or whichever direction we're going, whether it's up, down, left or right.
或者我们要去的任何方向 无论是上 下 左还是右
Once we've completed that, we can normalize everything again back to 0.0
一旦我们完成了这一点 我们可以再次将所有内容标准化为0.0
by doing self.currentroom equals, what do we need to do,
我们需要做的是
if we're going to put everything back to?
如果我们要把所有东西都放回去
Let's say I want to make this room the new current room.
假设我想把这个房间设为新的当前房间
What do I need to do?
我需要做什么？
So we have current room, and we have next room.
我们有当前房间 还有下一个房间
If I want the current room to become the next room,
如果我想让当前房间变成下一个房间
all I need to do is say self.currentroom equals self.nextroom, right?
我只需要说self.currencial等于self.nextreme 对吧？
And then once that happens, what happens to the adjacent
一旦发生这种情况
offset x and y of the next room?
下一个房间的x和y偏移量
They get set to 0, right?
他们被设置为0 对吧？
I want to take this room that we've offset up here,
我想把这个房间 我们已经抵消了这里
and I just want to make it the center of the game world again.
我只想让它再次成为游戏世界的中心
I want to just put it as 0.0, so we can do this exact same calculation
我只想把它设置为0.0 这样我们就可以进行完全相同的计算
by just setting adjacent offset x or y to a negative or positive screen height
只需将相邻的偏移量x或y设置为负或正屏幕高度
or screen width relative to 0.9.
或相对于0.9的屏幕宽度
So what I'm going to do is just set the adjacent offset
所以我要做的就是设置相邻的偏移量
of x and y of the next room, which is now current room, to 0.
将下一个房间(即当前房间)的x和y设置为0
And it's going to draw it right back at 0.0.
它会把它拉回到0.0
And then camera x and camera y are also going to be set to 0.0.
然后 相机x和相机y也将设置为0.0
And this is going to have the effect of looking as if we're going up
这将会产生一种效果 看起来就像我们正在上升
and staying there.
并留在那里
But in reality, we're just going up, and then
但在现实中 我们只是往上走 然后
instantly shifting everything back to 0.0,
立刻把一切都调回到了0度
including the player, entities, and switches of that room.
包括那个房间的玩家、实体和开关
So it's purely an illusion.
所以这纯粹是一种错觉
But it allows us to simulate this sort of infinite exploring a dungeon effect.
但它允许我们模拟这种无限探索地牢效应的过程
Does that make sense?
这说得通吗？
Does the overall flow of how this works makes sense?
这种工作方式的整体流程是否有意义？
OK.
好的
So it's a little bit messy there.
所以那里有点乱
Hopefully I was able to illustrate the overall algorithm for how
希望我能够说明整个算法是如何
the infinite dungeon generator works.
无限地牢发电机起作用了
Where did we leave off?
我们在哪里停下来了？
We were in the init function of the room.
我们在房间的初始功能中
So let's take a look at a few of the functions that comprise that.
因此 让我们来看看组成它的几个函数
So generate walls and floors.
因此 生成墙和地板
This is very similar to what we've looked
这与我们所看到的非常相似
at before with tile maps in Mario for example, where we just go from y to x.
以马里奥的瓷砖地图为例 我们只需从y到x
And then we just pick a random ID, or our random ID.
然后我们只需要选择一个随机的ID 或者我们的随机ID
Well, it is random ID for some of it.
嗯 其中一些是随机的身份证
But sometimes we need an explicit ID.
但有时我们需要一个明确的身份证明
So remind me, what does the ID actually map to when
所以提醒我 ID实际上映射到什么时候
we're you drawing tiles to the screen?
我们要把瓷砖画到屏幕上吗？
If we want to give a tile an ID, what does that, what should that map to?
如果我们想给一块瓷砖一个ID 那是什么 它应该映射到什么？
Yeah?
嗯?
AUDIENCE: The frame in the sprite sheet.
观众：精灵纸上的画框
COLTON OGDEN: The frame in the sprite sheet, that's correct.
科尔顿·奥格登：精灵图中的画框 没错
It doesn't have to for all game engines, for all implementations.
并不是所有的游戏引擎、所有的实现都必须如此
But it's the easiest thing to do, is just to give your tile an ID
但这是最容易做的事情 只需给您的切片一个ID
that you can then just draw, you can index
然后你就可以画出来 你可以编制索引
into your sprite sheet at that ID.
在你的精灵单子上用那个ID
It's just very, very simple, lightweight clean approach to modeling.
这是一种非常、非常简单、轻巧、干净的建模方法
And we can see here, ID gets ID.
我们可以在这里看到 ID得到了ID
After we've figured out what ID we want, now how
在我们弄清楚我们想要什么ID之后 现在如何
do we determine like let's say I want to draw--
我们是不是决定了 比如说我想画--
let's say, for example, like this tile here.
比方说 就像这块瓷砖
Notice it's a corner tile.
请注意 这是一块角瓷砖
What do I need to do to basically assign--
我需要做什么才能基本上分配--
I'm going to die before I even have the chance to show you.
我甚至在有机会给你看之前就要死了
While I avoid enemies, if I wanted to draw that top left corner,
在我躲避敌人的同时 如果我想画左上角
what am I sort of looking for?
我要找的是什么？
I'm still taking damage anyway.
不管怎么说 我还在承受损失
Relative to x and y, what am I looking for?
相对于x和y 我要找的是什么？
What x and y does that tile need, assuming
假设那块瓷砖需要多少x和y
everything starts 1.1 on the top left, and goes down
一切从左上角的1.1开始 然后向下
to height and width of the overall dungeon?
整个地牢的高度和宽度？
What is the xy need to be of that top left corner?
左上角的XY需要是什么？
It needs to be 1, right?
它应该是1 对吗？
So if that's 1.1, basically the top left corner,
所以如果是1.1 基本上就是左上角
that ID should be equal to the corner sprite.
该ID应等于角子画面
The top left corner sprite, specifically.
特别是左上角的精灵
What about the top right corner sprite?
那右上角的精灵呢？
What should the x be?
X应该是多少？
Sorry?
抱歉的?
AUDIENCE: Width.
观众：宽度
COLTON OGDEN: Yes, width.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的 宽度
Exactly.
一点儿没错
What's the y?
Y是多少？
Still going to be 1.
仍然是1
What about the bottom left?
左下角呢？
Width, comma height.
宽度、逗号高度
And then the bottom right?
然后是右下角？
AUDIENCE: But it's [INAUDIBLE]
观众：但这是[INAUDIBLE]
COLTON OGDEN: Sorry, bottom left should be 1, comma height.
科尔顿·奥格登：对不起 左下角应该是1 逗号高度
Bottom right should be width, height.
右下角应为宽度、高度
And so basically checking the position of each tile
所以基本上是检查每一块瓷砖的位置
is how we can infer its ID, which is what we're doing in the source code
是我们如何推断它的ID 这就是我们在源代码中所做的
here.
这里
If x is 1 and y is 1, OK, top left corner.
如果x是1 y是1 好的 左上角
And notice that we've put these into constants,
注意 我们已经将它们放入常量中
that we've put in the constant.lua, just for readability.
我们放在常量.lua中 只是为了可读性
So we can instantly see OK, I should set ID tile top left
所以我们可以立即看到OK 我应该将ID磁贴设置在左上方
corner, not some arbitrary number that's our index into the tile sheet.
角 而不是某个任意的数字 这是我们对瓷砖的索引
At maybe like 40 something, or whatever it is.
大概40多岁 或者其他什么年龄
Bottom left is 1 and height.
左下角是1和高度
Top right is width and 1, and then bottom right is width and height.
右上角是宽度和1 然后右下角是宽度和高度
And we can see, it's readable.
我们可以看到 它是可读的
We can sort of see at a glance what we're doing, where you're conditionally
我们可以一目了然地看到我们在做什么 你有条件地在哪里
generating all of our tiles.
生成我们所有的瓷砖
If none of those are true, and then x is 1, what's that tile?
如果这些都不是真的 那么x是1 那么这个瓦片是什么？
If x is 1, but it's not a corner?
如果x是1 但它不是一个角？
It's a left hand wall.
这是一面左手边的墙
And the same thing is if it's the width, it's a right hand wall.
同样的事情是 如果它是宽度 它就是右手边的墙
And if y is 1, it's a top wall.
如果y是1 它就是一面墙
If y is height, it's a bottom wall.
如果y是高度 那么它就是底部的墙
And then if it's none of those, it's got to be a floor, exactly.
如果不是这些 那就一定是一层楼
So that's basically how we generate the overall--
所以这基本上就是我们如何产生整体的--
it's a very easy, simple generation algorithm.
这是一个非常简单的生成算法
What I've done is for randomization here,
我在这里所做的是随机化
we have actually a table of potential left walls, potential right walls,
我们实际上有一张桌子 上面有潜在的左墙 潜在的右墙
potential top and bottom.
潜在的顶部和底部
And then we just ascribe it a random value within there,
然后我们只需在其中指定一个随机值
based on however large that is.
基于它的规模有多大
And that gives us variable, we can see it.
这给了我们变量 我们可以看到它
We have random-- every time I generate it.
我们有随机性--每次我产生它
So take note of maybe some of the tiles visually
所以请注意视觉上的一些瓷砖
that you can see there on the map.
你可以在地图上看到
Notice that they change.
请注意 它们会发生变化
Notice that the switch has also changed.
请注意 交换机也已更改
Notice that they changed again.
请注意 它们再次更改
So everything is variable.
因此 一切都是可变的
We have a little bit of visual variety.
我们有一点视觉上的多样性
This is what we did, essentially, with Mario.
基本上 这就是我们对马里奥所做的
We changed the tile set, and the topper set.
我们换了瓷砖套装和顶层套装
Only now we're just changing, we have only one tile sheet,
只是现在我们只是在改变 我们只有一张瓷砖
but several variations at the same tile they're in.
但在同一块瓷砖上有几种不同的变化
So all we need to do is pick a random variation of whatever tile.
所以我们所要做的就是随机选择任何瓷砖的变体
And that involves us looking at the sprite sheet,
这涉及到我们查看精灵薄片
picking out which individual tiles, which separate tiles,
挑选出哪些单独的瓷砖 哪些瓷砖分开
map to the specific type of tile, and then just picking a random value
映射到特定类型的切片 然后只需选取一个随机值
from that table
从那张桌子上
That's how that works.
这就是它的工作原理
So a couple of things, I think, left to show relative
所以 我认为 有几件事需要向亲人展示
to the dungeon generation.
敬地牢一代
So 48, we have generate entities.
因此 我们已经生成了48个实体
So entities are here.
因此 实体在这里
We have their names, right?
我们知道他们的名字 对吧？
Some of the entities we saw, skeletons, bats, slimes, ghosts, spiders.
我们看到的一些实体 骷髅 蝙蝠 粘液 鬼魂 蜘蛛
It's a very lightweight function.
这是一个非常轻量级的功能
It's not like 15 or 20 lines, but we're generating
它不像15或20行 但我们正在生成
a bunch of different kinds of entities.
a bunch束of different不同kinds种类of entities实体.
Because what we've done, we take, we basically
因为我们所做的 我们基本上
take a random type from that table.
从表中随机选择一种类型
We create an entity, and then using what we've
我们创建一个实体 然后使用我们所拥有的
defined in a global table called Entity Defs,
定义在一个叫做实体定义的全局表中
we take out what sort of matters in terms
我们把重要的东西
of generating each individual entity, the characteristics thereof,
每一个个体的产生 其特征
and we just put it in simple data form.
我们把它转换成简单的数据形式
This is sort of like the segue into data driven design for your game.
这有点像游戏的数据驱动设计
If you look at Entity Defs here, we can just see that all of our entities
如果你看这里的实体定义 我们可以看到所有的实体
are a sequence of data.
是一系列数据
So up here we have player, on line 10.
这里有一个参与人 在第10行.
Player gets a table.
玩家得到一张桌子
We give him walk speed.
我们给他步行速度
We have a table of animations.
我们有一个动画表
So he's got a walk left animation, a walk right animation,
所以他有一个向左走的动画 一个向右走的动画
a walk down animation.
走下动画
All of those have their frames, their interval, their texture, everything
所有这些都有它们的框架 它们的间隔 它们的纹理 一切
is just clean data, right?
就是干净的数据对吧
There's no logic here, really.
这里没有逻辑 真的
It's just flags, or values, simple things.
只是一些标志 或者值 简单的东西
You could give anybody who has sort of the basic knowledge of what we're
你可以给任何对我们的基本知识有一定了解的人
doing this file, and maybe some textures, and say, hey,
做这个文件 也许还有一些纹理 然后说 嘿
I want you to design--
我想让你设计
I want you to lay out basically all of that's
我要你把所有的东西
involved in what makes a skeleton render to the screen.
参与了骨架在屏幕上的渲染
Create all the animations for them.
为他们制作所有的动画
Give those animations their timing.
给这些动画计时
Give them the exact frames.
给他们准确的框架
Maybe skeletons should have health, and maybe health should be equal to 10
也许骨架应该有健康值 也许健康值应该等于10
on a skeleton, or something like that.
在一具骨架上 或者类似的东西上
There's not really any programming going on here.
实际上这里没有任何编程
But we're describing everything in our game as data.
但我们把游戏中的一切都描述成数据
And that's important thing in complex games that have fairly complex systems,
这在复杂的游戏中是很重要的 因为游戏系统相当复杂
but that can be modeled via some attributes.
但是可以通过一些属性来建模
You can just ascribe your entities and data, and then let your engine parse
您可以只归属于实体和数据 然后让引擎解析
this information, and then create your entities programmatically.
此信息 然后以编程方式创建您的实体
You shift the burden from the programmer to the designer, a little bit.
稍微把负担从程序员转移到设计者身上
And you afford your design team, you and maybe other people
你请得起你的设计团队 你 也许还有其他人
who aren't as comfortable with programming,
对编程不太熟悉的人
the ability to modify the game engine, add things to the game,
能够修改游戏引擎 向游戏中添加内容
without having to go through the bulk of your engine code
而不必查看大量的引擎代码
and do anything too fancy.
做任何太花哨的事
In this case, it's simple.
在这种情况下 它很简单
All we're doing is just we're creating animations, and assigning a texture
我们所做的只是创建动画 并指定一个纹理
to each of these individual things.
这些个体中的每一种
But I alluded to this last week.
但我上周曾暗示过这一点
You can have a file that maybe describes something like a goblin.
你可以有一个文件 它可能描述了一些类似地精的东西
We'll see this at the end of a lecture, which has maybe like a flag
我们会在一堂课的最后看到这一点 它可能像一面旗帜
for is it flammable?
因为它是易燃的吗？
How much health does it have?
它的生命力有多强？
What are its animations?
它的动画是什么？
What skills does it have?
它有什么技能？
What's its attack strength?
它的进攻强度有多大？
What's its defense?
它的辩护理由是什么？
Where does it spawn typically?
它通常在哪里产卵？
By putting all these attributes together and having your engine sort of parse
通过将所有这些属性放在一起并让您的引擎进行某种解析
this, you can create, depending on how many fields you have,
这个 你可以创建 取决于你有多少个字段
you can create very complex potential list of things in your game.
你可以在你的游戏中创建非常复杂的潜在清单
Whether they're entities, whether they're weapons, whether they're items,
无论他们是实体 无论是武器 还是物品
abilities.
超能力
Anything you want to.
任何你想做的事
Whether they're levels, even.
不管它们是不是水平
Based solely on just data.
仅仅基于数据
So this is a holy grail of design and development
因此 这是设计和开发的圣杯
when you get into especially very complex games like RPGs,
当你进入像RPG这样特别复杂的游戏时
where you can have skills that have particle effects
在那里你可以拥有具有粒子效果的技能
and do different damage to different things.
对不同的东西造成不同的伤害
And you have entities that are-- maybe you want them some to set on fire,
你有一些实体--也许你想让它们被烧毁
some to be electrocuted.
有些人会触电身亡
Maybe some you don't.
也许有些你不知道
Maybe some melt when they touch something.
也许当他们接触到什么东西时 一些会融化
Create a bunch of flags, create a function
创建一串旗帜 创建一个函数
that parses this, and generates entities as a result.
它对此进行解析 并生成结果实体
And you just allow yourself an incredible boost in productivity.
你只需要让你自己的工作效率得到令人难以置信的提升
No longer do you need to create a spider class, a ghost class, a bat class.
您不再需要创建蜘蛛类、幽灵类、蝙蝠类
It's all unnecessary.
这都是不必要的
All you need to do is define what sort of attributes does a bat have?
你所需要做的就是定义蝙蝠有哪些属性？
What attributes does a ghost have?
幽灵有什么属性？
What attributes does a skeleton have?
骨架有哪些属性？
And anybody can therefore mod your game as a result of this.
因此 任何人都可以因此修改您的游戏
All they need to do is know what attributes a potential entity can have.
他们所需要做的就是知道一个潜在实体可以具有哪些属性
And your design team is all the more productive as a result.
因此 您的设计团队的工作效率会更高
So that's a spiel on why this is relevant.
所以这就是为什么这是一个相关的说辞
We've implemented a very basic version of this
我们已经实现了一个非常基本的版本
just for the sake of modeling animations.
只是为了制作动画模型
But we don't need a separate class for all the different entities in our game
但我们不需要为游戏中的所有不同实体创建单独的类
world.
世界
We just need, basically, and in the context of this game,
我们只需要 基本上 在这个游戏的背景下
what are their animations?
他们的动画是什么？
So that's entity defs, that's how it's working if we're
这就是实体定义 这就是它的工作方式 如果我们
looking at room.lua at line 48.
看看第48行的room.lua
All its doing is getting animations.
它所做的一切就是制作动画
This is, by the way, your function that takes in these definitions
顺便说一句 这是您的函数 它接受这些定义
and creates your entities.
并创建你的实体
They should be looking for--
他们应该寻找--
looking into that.
正在调查这件事
They pull that definition and then just parse out
他们提取该定义 然后解析出
each individual relevant piece of data.
每一条相关的数据
And then just construct some relevant information
然后只需构建一些相关信息
or attach a relevant flag to that entity that your game engine can then later
或将相关标志附加到该实体 以便您的游戏引擎稍后可以
parse.
解析
The flammable example, if you do an attack and that attack is of type fire,
举个易燃的例子 如果你进行攻击 而攻击是火力类型的
and it collides with an entity, and that entity.flammable is true,
它与一个实体相撞 这个实体 易燃是真的
that should trigger some behavior.
这应该会引发一些行为
But you don't need to do anything terribly complex.
但你不需要做任何非常复杂的事情
And you can assign this to any arbitrary entity thereafter.
此后 您可以将其分配给任何任意实体
So just a simple way of getting very complex behavior for your game
所以 这只是一种简单的方法来获取游戏中非常复杂的行为
objects, entities, whatever you want.
对象 实体 任何你想要的东西
Modeling them as data rather than thinking about it in terms of classes.
将它们建模为数据 而不是从类的角度考虑
So that's that.
就是这样
Does anybody have any questions just like sort of how that works,
有没有人有任何问题 比如它是如何工作的
or why it's viable?
或者为什么它是可行的？
Or why it's useful?
或者为什么它有用？
OK.
好的
Couple of last things we'll look at really fast in room.
最后几件事 我们会在房间里快速看一看
So online 82.
所以上网82
Generate objects.
生成对象
So we did this very, very similarly last week.
所以我们上周做了非常非常相似的事情
Where we just had a game object class.
在那里我们刚刚有了一个游戏对象类
Notice that it takes itself a definition for a switch.
请注意 它本身就是一个交换机的定义
That definition is in gameobjects.lua.
这个定义在游戏对象.lua中
Switch.
换个位置
Here's a little bit more sort of data modeling something like a switch.
这是一种更类似于开关的数据建模
It's got a type of switch, frame is 2 by default. So width and height of 16.
它有一种类型的开关 默认的帧是2 所以宽度和高度都是16
It's not solid.
它并不结实
Player can walk over it.
玩家可以走过去
Its default state is upressed.
其默认状态为抑制
So when it gets spawned into the game, it's unpressed.
因此 当它被催生到游戏中时 它是不受压力的
And it's got two potential states, unprecedented and pressed.
它有两种潜在的状态 史无前例的和紧迫的
And each of those states have a frame.
这些州中的每一个都有一个框架
So all we need to do to render it is say, what's its current state?
所以我们要做的就是呈现它 它的当前状态是什么？
Render this state.frame.
呈现此状态 帧
And then now, we don't need to do anything--
然后现在 我们不需要做任何事情--
that's basically all we need to do in order to render it at the right point.
这基本上就是我们所需要做的 以便在正确的点上呈现它
Your game engine, therefore, needs to look at your object,
因此 您的游戏引擎需要查看对象
and look at its state and look at its potential states, index into that state
并查看其状态和潜在状态 索引到该状态
and then pull the frame from that.
然后从那里拉出框架
But it forwards you sort of infinite flexibility.
但它为你提供了一种无限的灵活性
You can now have maybe of a glowing state,
你现在可以有一个发光的状态
and maybe there's a frame in that sprite sheet that allows it to glow.
也许在那张精灵纸上有一个框架让它发光
And you could just change it to glowing whenever you want,
你可以随时随地把它换成发光
and it'll just render appropriately.
它会恰到好处地渲染
So very flexible approach to modeling data.
所以对数据建模的方法非常灵活
149 in room.
房间有149个房间
So we're almost done with the dungeon here.
所以我们快完成这里的地牢了
So 149 is our update function.
所以149是我们的更新功能
All it does basically is iterate through everything
它所做的基本上就是遍历所有内容
and update it, including basically all the entities.
并更新它 基本上包括所有实体
So for every entity if its health is less than or equal to 0, it's dead.
所以对于每个实体来说 如果它的生命值小于或等于0 它就是死的
If it's dead, then don't render it, which we see down in render.
如果它是死的 那么不要渲染它 我们在渲染中看到了这一点
But if it's not dead, and self.player player collides with it,
但如果它没有死 而且玩家自己撞到了它
and the player's not vulnerable, then we should damage the player,
而且玩家并不脆弱 那么我们就应该伤害玩家
go invulnerable.
变得无懈可击
And if the player's health is zero, change to game over.
如果玩家的健康状况为零 则切换到游戏结束
So notice how readable this is.
所以请注意这是多么的可读性
When you model your entities like this as well, all you really need to do
当您也像这样对实体建模时 您真正需要做的就是
is just check for certain flags or functions,
只是检查某些标志或函数
and you can do arbitrarily complex tests like this.
你可以像这样做任意复杂的测试
Because entities can be dead, or not.
因为实体可能是死的 也可能不是
Because entities can be invulnerable, or not.
因为实体可以是无懈可击的 也可以不是
And then because entities are all xy, with height based things in our game,
然后因为实体都是XY的 在我们的游戏中基于高度的东西
and collide just expects them to have that.
而碰撞只是希望他们拥有这一点
All we just do is play sound, damage the player.
我们所做的只是播放声音 伤害玩家
What does damage do offhand?
伤害在即刻会造成什么影响？
What do you think it does?
你觉得它能做什么？
AUDIENCE: I'll take a wild guess and say subtracts from your health.
观众：我会胡乱猜测 然后说减去你的健康
COLTON OGDEN: Exactly.
科尔顿·奥格登：没错
Just take a wild guess and say it subtracts from health.
随便猜一猜 就会说它有损健康
It does.
确实如此
So entity damage just takes in a number, and subtracts that from health.
所以实体伤害只是一个数字 然后从生命值中减去这个数字
That's all it does.
这就是它的全部功能
Go invulnerable.
变得无懈可击
What does that do.
那是做什么的
AUDIENCE: Means you've been taking damage for that many seconds?
观众：这意味着你已经遭受了那么多秒的伤害？
COLTON OGDEN: It does.
科尔顿·奥格登：的确如此
It prevents you from taking damage for that many seconds.
它可以防止你在那么长的时间内受到伤害
All that really does is just set a flag, which I've alluded to quite a bit
所有这些实际上只是设置了一个标志 我已经提到了很多
already, an arbitrary flag that you can model via data or some other means.
已经是一个任意的标志 您可以通过数据或其他方式进行建模
Every entity has an invulnerable flag.
每个实体都有一面坚不可摧的旗帜
And if it's invulnerable, then the engine should look for that,
如果它是无懈可击的 那么引擎应该寻找它
and change the rendering, and the mechanics of the entity accordingly.
并相应地更改渲染和实体的机制
And then lastly here, just simple if the player health is equal to 0,
最后这里 很简单 如果玩家的健康等于0
which it might be after we take sufficient damage, change to Game Over.
这可能是在我们受到足够的伤害后 更改为游戏结束
That's all it does.
这就是它的全部功能
And then for every object, just as we do with every entity, update the object
然后 对于每个对象 就像我们对每个实体所做的那样 更新对象
and if the player collides with it, then trigger its On Collide function.
如果玩家与其相撞 则触发其碰撞功能
And this can be a function that you arbitrarily create,
这可以是你任意创建的函数
depending on the needs of your object.
取决于您的对象的需求
If you look up here, for example, every time we create a room,
例如 如果你抬头看这里 每次我们创建一个房间
we generate objects in the room.
我们在房间里生成对象
We insert into objects a switch, which we saw before, in gameobjects.lua.
我们在对象中插入了一个开关 这是我们在前面看到的 在gameobjects.lua中
And takes an x and a y.
取x和y
In this case, we just make sure that the x and y
在这种情况下 我们只需确保x和y
is a random number between the top left of the map
是地图左上角之间的一个随机数
and the bottom right of the map, within the padding that it has.
和地图的右下角 在它所具有的填充内
We get a reference to that object.
我们得到了对该对象的引用
And then we define are On Collide function.
然后定义了Are on Collide函数
So what we do is we say if it's upressed,
所以我们要做的就是说如果它被压制了
so recall that we have a state in the game object definition.
回想一下 我们在游戏对象定义中有一个状态
If it's unpressed, change it to pressed.
如果是未熨烫的 就改成熨烫
It's all we really need to do.
这就是我们真正需要做的
And then notice here, for k, a doorway.
然后注意这里 比如k 有一扇门
So for every doorway in doorways, self.doorways, set that doorway open
因此 对于每一扇门 无论是自己的门 都要把门敞开
is true.
是真的
And then play a door sound.
然后播放一声门声
So our On Collide function just interacts
所以我们的On Collide函数只是相互作用
with other things in the game world, and just very simple things
与游戏世界中的其他东西 以及非常简单的东西
but has a pretty interesting sort of mechanic.
但有一种非常有趣的机械师
Like we have a--
就像我们有一个...
I took damage off the bat there, because my spawning isn't perfect.
我从蝙蝠那里得到了伤害 因为我的产卵并不完美
But it changed from-- notice that it changed its state from unpressed
但它从--请注意 它的状态从未按下更改
to pressed.
按下
Because it went from the one sprite to--
因为它从唯一的精灵变成了--
I'll go into another room so we can see that.
我去另一个房间 这样我们就能看到了
I'll take some damage on the way.
我会在路上弄坏一些东西
Go to another room.
去另一个房间
Notice the sprite.
请注意精灵
It sort of looks like it's unpressed, right?
它看起来像是没有被压住的 对吗？
Because the game object's default state is unpressed.
因为游戏对象的默认状态是未按下的
And then On Collide triggers when I go on top of it.
然后当我在它上面的时候就会触发碰撞
It changes state, which has an effect on what gets rendered.
它会更改状态 这会对渲染的内容产生影响
And it's On Collide function is called, which
它是关于Collide函数的调用 该函数
opened up every doorway in the room.
把房间的每一扇门都打开了
So simple like 15 lines of code.
如此简单 就像15行代码
But pretty compelling, interesting behavior for the sake of our dungeon.
但为了我们的地牢 我们的行为很吸引人 很有趣
Like, it adds a lot, as simple as that is.
就像 它增加了很多东西 就这么简单
Now we sort of feel like we're interacting
现在我们感觉就像是在互动
with our game world a little bit.
和我们的游戏世界有一点关系
So that's how that works.
这就是它的工作原理
And then lastly, rendering on line 188.
最后 在第188行上进行渲染
Just go through all of our tiles, render all the tiles.
只需检查我们所有的瓷砖 渲染所有瓷砖
We've seen this before.
我们以前见过这种情况
Render all the doorways, render all the objects,
渲染所有的门口 渲染所有的物体
render all the entities, if they're not dead.
渲染所有实体 如果它们没有死的话
Right?
对吗？
If they're dead, then don't render them.
如果它们已经死了 那么就不要渲染它们
And then this bit here, we'll take a look at the end, which is stenciling.
然后这一点 我们将看看结尾 这是模版
So notice that when I walk through doors.
所以请注意当我走进门的时候
Well first of all, notice that I can't walk through doors if they're closed,
首先 请注意 如果门是关着的 我是不能走进去的
which is important.
这一点很重要
So when you collide with your doorway objects, if doorway.Open is false,
因此 当你与门口的物体碰撞时 如果Doorway.Open为False
it shouldn't trigger the room switch, right?
它不应该触发房间开关 对吗？
But if I open the doors they're now all set to recall.
但如果我打开门 它们现在都会被召回
Door.open is now equal to true.
Door.open现在等于True
So they've changed their renderings, and now they're rendering open doorways.
所以他们改变了他们的渲染 现在他们正在渲染开放的门口
If I walk through it, notice that it looks as if the player walks
如果我穿过它 注意到它看起来像是玩家走的
underneath the tiles.
在瓷砖下面
But I'm drawing the tiles before the player.
但我是在玩家面前画牌
And one approach that you might think to do
还有一种你可能认为应该做的方法
when sort of creating this believable appearance of walking
当创造出这种令人信服的行走外观时
through a doorway, is say OK.
穿过一扇门 就是说好
I'll just render the player after I render before I render the doorways.
我只会在渲染之后渲染播放器 然后再渲染门口
Right?
对吗？
So render all the doorways last.
所以最后渲染所有的门
But it doesn't quite work out, because the sprite actually starts right here.
但这并不是很有效 因为精灵实际上就是从这里开始的
So what does somebody think is going to happen if I were
所以有人会认为如果我是
to draw the doorway after the player?
在玩家身后画门口吗？
AUDIENCE: Your default player disappears if you cross that line or [INAUDIBLE]
观众：如果你越过这条线或[INAUDIBLE] 你的默认玩家就会消失
over that line.
越过那条线
COLTON OGDEN: Exactly.
科尔顿·奥格登：没错
The player would disappear as soon as he gets to this little bit of line right
球员一走到这一小段线就会消失
here, which is not very convincing.
在这里 这不是很有说服力
And actually I'll try right now to take away the stenciling,
实际上 我现在就试着去掉模版
so we can see what that looks like.
这样我们就能看到那是什么样子了
So if I just take away the stenciling here, and then I just render.
所以如果我去掉这里的模板 然后我只需要渲染
Can't type today.
今天不能打字
So I'm going to go ahead.
所以我要继续了
Do that.
那就去吧
Well, first of all, the rendering order is such that now the doorways render
首先 渲染顺序是这样的 现在门口渲染
after before the player.
在球员之前
So he just walks right over them, right?
所以他就直接从他们身上走过去 对吗？
So I'm just walking, I was walking over the walls.
所以我只是在走 我是在跨过墙
That's not compelling.
这并不令人信服
And if I were to do something as simple as change the rendering order.
如果我要做一些简单的事情 比如改变渲染顺序
So right now, the doorways render first.
因此 现在 门口首先进行渲染
I'll just render the doorways after the player.
我将在玩家之后渲染门口
So right here, I took that out, right?
所以就在这里 我把它拿出来了 对吗？
No.
不是的
So right now, they render before the player.
所以现在 他们在玩家面前进行渲染
I want to render them after the player.
我想按照玩家的名字来渲染它们
And I'm going to just run it.
我要把它运行起来
And then going to step on the switch.
然后踩下开关
And then, yep.
然后 是的
Notice we get some weird behavior, too.
请注意 我们也会遇到一些奇怪的行为
Like sees his head is getting cut off?
就像看到他的头被砍掉一样？
And other entities as well, right?
以及其他实体也是如此 对吗？
In that case, I couldn't really tell.
在这种情况下 我真的看不出来
But yeah.
不过 是的
Very weird rending behavior.
非常奇怪的撕裂行为
And what we do to fix that is we create what's called a stencil.
我们要做的就是创造一种被称为模板的东西
So basically I'll try and get a screenshot here I can show.
因此 基本上我会尝试获得一个屏幕截图 我可以在这里展示
First let me fix the changes that I just made.
首先 让我修改一下我刚才所做的更改
Right.
正确的
And then if I go back into the code here.
然后如果我回到这里的代码
So a stencil is just-- and we'll see a slide on this in a little bit.
所以模板只是--我们稍后会看到一张幻灯片
But a stencil is just basically any sort of arbitrary shape that want,
但模板基本上是任何类型的任意形状
that you draw onto the screen.
你画在屏幕上的
It's invisible, but it determines whatever
它是看不见的 但它决定了
gets drawn on top of that stencil, it determines whether or not
在该模板上绘制 它确定是否
that thing gets rendered.
那东西就会被渲染
So I have a stencil going basically from here onwards to the next room.
所以我有一个模板 基本上是从这里一直到下一个房间
So right about where the doorway hits the archway,
所以就在门口撞到拱门的地方
because that's where we want the player's head
因为这就是我们想要玩家的头
to look like it disappears.
让它看起来像是消失了
Stencil going here.
模板放在这里
I have a stencil going right here.
我这里有一支钢笔
And right here.
就在这里
And on the right side as well.
在右边也是如此
And what that does is I've set the stencil
这样做的目的是我已经设置了模板
to say whatever passes through this stencil during the sort
说出在分类过程中通过这个模板的任何东西
of stencil testing period which is, well all we do is we just
模板测试期 我们所做的只是
draw the player during that time.
在这段时间内画出玩家
But basically if it's on the stencil, don't render it.
但基本上 如果它在模板上 就不会呈现它
And so it what that has the effect of is we still
所以它的影响是我们仍然
draw the doorways before the player.
在玩家面前画出门道
So the player walks in and he's drawn above this part.
所以球员走进来 他被拉到了这一部分的上方
But as soon as he hits the stencil, he's not drawn.
但一旦他打到模板 他就没有被画出来
It just-- all those, basically what it does
它只是--所有这些 基本上它所做的
is it draws the character to the stencil, and not to the actual canvas.
它将字符绘制到模具上 而不是实际的画布上
And so we get if you want convincing layered, weird, visual effects
因此 如果你想要令人信服的分层、怪异的视觉效果
like that, stenciling is an approach.
就像这样 模版是一种方法
OK.
好的
And then that's all this.
然后就是这一切
So this stencil function, love.graphics.stencil,
所以这个模板函数 love.graph 模板
takes in a function.
接受一个函数
This is what's going to run during the actual stenciling process.
这是在实际的模版过程中要运行的内容
It's going to draw--
它将会抽签--
I draw four rectangles.
我画了四个矩形
All those rectangles are just those archways.
所有那些矩形就是那些拱门
Right?
对吗？
Perfectly layered over them such that it goes into the next room.
完美地覆盖在它们上面 这样它就可以进入隔壁的房间
And then we do.
然后我们就这么做了
Notice that it says Replace, and then 1.
请注意 它显示的是替换 然后是1
So we replace any pixel that gets drawn to that stencil
因此 我们替换绘制到该模板上的任何像素
with the stencil value of 1.
模板值为1
And then we only draw things that are less than 1 during the stencil test.
然后我们只在模具测试中画小于1的东西
Which means anything that didn't get ascribed to value of 1, which
这意味着任何没有被归因于值1的东西
means that if the player went over the stencil,
也就是说 如果玩家翻阅了模板
got a pixel value of 1, that's going to be false.
得到的像素值为1 则为假
He's not going to be drawn to the screen.
他不会被屏幕所吸引
Yes?
是?
AUDIENCE: So you are stenciling, if you created a different shape,
观众：所以你是在刻版 如果你创造了一个不同的形状
you could use that, for say, like a light system, some areas are dark,
你可以利用这一点 比如说 像灯光系统一样 一些区域是黑暗的
some areas are light?
有些区域是亮的吗？
COLTON OGDEN: Good question was if you have a stencil, because you
科尔顿·奥格登：很好的问题是 如果你有一个模板 因为你
can do with an arbitrary shape, you could
可以使用任意形状 您可以
create lighting systems where some areas are dark, and some areas are light.
在某些区域为暗区域 而某些区域为亮区域的情况下创建照明系统
I want to say possibly.
我想说有可能
The thing is, I'm not 100% sure whether stenciling allows you to do,
问题是 我不能100%确定模板是否允许你这样做
whether love 2D stenciling allows you to do arbitrary numbers.
爱2D模板是否允许你做任意的数字
I basically am not sure if it's on or off, or a gradient.
我基本上不确定它是开着还是关着 还是渐变
Typically, if I were to do our lighting system like that,
通常 如果我这样做我们的照明系统
I would probably draw a faux lighting system.
我可能会画一个假的照明系统
One, you can use a lighting kit, like box
第一 你可以使用照明套件 比如盒子
2D lights, which does really compelling, cool lights for you.
2D灯光 这对你来说真的很吸引人 很酷的灯光
Or sort of a cruder way to do it, but possibly realistic,
或者是一种更粗鲁的方式 但也可能是现实的
would be to draw a shape that fits whatever you want to be your darkness,
就是画一个形状 适合你想要成为黑暗的任何东西
and then render it at an opacity that's less than 100%.
然后以低于100%的不透明度进行渲染
So you'd have a room, and let's say maybe to sides of it
所以你会有一个房间 比方说可能在它的两边
are kind of shadowy.
都有些模糊
You draw black rectangles there, right?
你在那里画黑色的矩形 对吗？
But instead of drawing those black rectangles at 255 alpha,
但是 这些黑色矩形不是以255阿尔法绘制的
you draw them at 200 or 150, or something like that.
你把它们画在200或150 或者类似的地方
And so you can still see what's underneath them,
所以你仍然可以看到它们下面是什么
but it looks as if they are a shadow.
但看起来它们似乎是一个影子
And you can use gradient effects to do the same thing.
你可以使用渐变效果来做同样的事情
If you want to have shadow that's darker going lighter,
如果你想要更深更浅的阴影
I believe you can draw rectangles with a gradient effect in Love 2D.
我相信你可以在Love 2D中画出带有渐变效果的矩形
I'd have to look into a little bit more.
我还得再深入调查一下
But you would look to do something like that.
但你会想要做这样的事
Draw a gradient of shadow via some rectangle, or some arbitrary shape,
通过某个矩形或任意形状绘制阴影的渐变
to simulate lighting in that case.
在这种情况下模拟照明
And you could accomplish something similar to that.
你可以完成类似的事情
And there are a lot of other crazy cool ways I've seeing lightning done in 2D.
还有很多其他疯狂的很酷的方式 我在2D中看到过闪电
But that's probably offhand the simplest way that I could think of doing it.
但这可能是我能想到的最简单的方法了
Cool.
凉爽的
So that's stenciling, and that's basically it
所以这就是模版 基本上就是这样
for the dungeon generation, which is arguably the most important part.
对于地牢一代来说 这可以说是最重要的部分
And also we looked earlier at the sort of transition mechanic.
我们之前也看过这种过渡机制
And we'll look at the transition mechanic a little bit more
我们将更多地了解过渡机械师
in a little bit.
稍等片刻
But let's take a five minute for right now, and then come back to that
但让我们现在花五分钟 然后回到那个问题上
and see some more stuff.
再看看更多的东西
All right.
好的
Welcome back to Lecture 5, Legend of Zelda.
欢迎回到第五讲 塞尔达传奇
So before the break, we talked about a bunch
所以在休息之前 我们谈到了一些
of different things, dungeon generation being foremost among them.
在不同的事物中 地牢一代是其中最重要的
Now we'll actually start talking about things like hitboxes and hurtboxes,
现在我们将真正开始谈论像Hitbox和Hurtbox这样的东西
as we can see here on the screen.
正如我们在屏幕上看到的那样
So a hitbox is a rectangle, basically.
因此 Hitbox基本上是一个长方形
And it's how we've implemented it in the distro.
这就是我们在发行版中实现它的方式
But we can see here there's a few different sort
但我们在这里可以看到有几种不同的
of rectangles overlapping.
矩形重叠的部分
We have the green rectangles here.
我们这里有绿色的长方形
These are hurtboxes.
这些都是伤害箱
These are where you can get hurt.
这就是你可能受伤的地方
And then this is a hitbox.
然后这是一个Hitbox
This is where you can hit something.
这是你可以击球的地方
And so games, like especially with fighting games,
所以游戏 特别是格斗游戏
in a lot of games of fairly complex interactions,
在许多相当复杂的互动游戏中
and complex entities that have weapons or particles,
以及拥有武器或粒子的复杂实体
things like that all do damage.
诸如此类的事情都会造成损害
You'll see a lot of complicated overlapping,
你会看到很多复杂的重叠
and arrangement of these rectangles that sort of bring about
以及这些矩形的排列 这就带来了
how things interact with each other in terms of collision,
物体如何在碰撞方面相互作用
and doing damage, and affecting other entities.
造成损害 并影响到其他实体
In this case, he's doing an attack that goes from the left to the right.
在这种情况下 他正在进行从左到右的攻击
It's a low attack.
这是一次低位进攻
Only his foot, essentially, a little bit inwards.
只是他的脚 从本质上讲 有点向内
But essentially his foot does damage, whereas the rest of him is vulnerable.
但从本质上说 他的脚是有损伤的 而他的其余部分是脆弱的
If someone were to come up to him from up above and attack him,
如果有人从上面走到他跟前攻击他
it would do some damage.
这会造成一些损害
And there's Minecraft, and it shows you how the same sort of principle
还有《我的世界》 它向你展示了同样的原则
applies to 3D games as well.
同样适用于3D游戏
In this case, what you see there are all hurtboxes.
在这种情况下 你看到的都是伤害箱
Those are all aware things can get hurt.
这些人都意识到事情可能会受到伤害
Even though those are few of those things are items,
尽管这些东西很少是物品
so that only really affects whether or not the player collides with them
因此 这只会真正影响玩家是否与它们相撞
and picks them up.
然后把它们捡起来
But that's basically the difference between hitboxes and hurtboxes.
但这基本上就是Hitbox和Hurtbox之间的区别
The distro I think I accidentally called the file hurtbox.
我想我不小心把这个文件命名为hurtbox的发行版
So when I push it up, it's going to be renamed hitbox,
所以当我把它往上推时 它会被重新命名为Hitbox
because that's what we use it for.
因为这就是我们使用它的目的
But what is offhand in this game, what do we need a hitbox for?
但在这场比赛中有什么是即兴的 我们需要Hitbox做什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] attacks from the swoord.
观众：[听不见]呼啸而来的攻击
COLTON OGDEN: Attacks with a sword.
科尔顿·奥格登：用剑攻击
And the reason that we need a hitbox for that is why?
我们需要Hitbox的原因是什么？
AUDIENCE: To [INAUDIBLE] the hit.
观众：致[INAUDIBLE]大热
COLTON OGDEN: Yes.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
And why can't we just use the player's position x-y width and height?
为什么我们不能只使用球员的位置x-y宽度和高度？
AUDIENCE: Because it has a direction as well.
观众：因为它也有一个方向
COLTON OGDEN: Because it has a direction as well, and also it needs--
科尔顿·奥格登：因为它也有方向 也需要--
that's essentially its hurtbox.
这基本上就是它的伤害性武器
Right?
对吗？
So those two reasons.
所以这两个原因
It has that direction that we need to sort of act as its reference point
它有我们需要作为它参考点的方向
for generating a hit box, to inflict damage on other entities.
用于生成命中框 对其他实体造成伤害
And we need to use the player's main hitbox
我们需要使用玩家的主Hitbox
and hurtbox that it already has to see if something
以及伤害盒 它已经必须看看是否有什么东西
hit it, the player, maybe from another side, or something like that.
击球 球员 也许是从另一边 或者类似的东西
So let's go ahead and take a look here.
那么 让我们继续下去 看看这里
The main bit of code that deals with the hitbox, in this case,
处理Hitbox的主要代码 在本例中
is one going to be hurtbox.
其中一个将会成为伤害盒
Should be hitbox.
应该是希特波斯
But we can see this is literally just a rectangle class.
但我们可以看到 这实际上只是一个矩形类
xy, a width and a height.
XY 宽度和高度
self.x, self.y, self-taught, self.width, self.height equals all those things.
自学 自学
That's all you need for a hitbox.
这就是你对Hitbox所需要的一切
Literally box, just all you need are those fields.
字面意思就是盒子 你所需要的就是那些字段
And then you can do simply collides.
然后你可以做简单的碰撞
Just like you do entity.
就像你做实体一样
Entity collides hurtbox.
实体碰撞伤害箱
Yes, no, true or false.
是 不 对或错
Because recall, collides expects xy width or height.
因为回想起来 碰撞预期XY宽度或高度
And it's defined an entity.lua.
它定义了一个整体Lua
So if we go up to the player states.
因此 如果我们上升到玩家状态
So recall, last week we introduced the idea
回想一下 上周我们介绍了这个想法
of having the player maintain its own collection of states,
让玩家维护自己的状态集合
in a state machine.
在状态机中
As opposed to just the game world having a state machine that
而不仅仅是游戏世界有一个状态机
influences whether we're at the Start screen,
影响我们是否在开始屏幕上
the Play State screen, whatever we want to divide our game up into.
Play State屏幕 无论我们想要将游戏划分成什么
We have entities states as well.
我们也有实体国家
Now one of those is the-- so we have the idle in the walk state.
其中之一是--所以我们在行走状态下有空闲的
Those are so very similar to last week's, where the idle state, they're
这些与上周的非常相似 空闲状态 他们是
just standing still.
只是站着不动
And the walking state they're moving and their animation changes accordingly.
以及它们正在移动的行走状态 它们的动画也会相应地改变
The swing sword state is a new state, and what this does
摆剑状态是一个新的状态 而这个状态的作用是
is the player presses spacebar.
是玩家按空格键
It triggers this swing sword state.
它会触发这种摇摆的剑状态
There's a new animation.
有一部新的动画
So we go into the swing sword animation, relative to which direction we're in.
因此 我们进入摆动剑动画 相对于我们所处的方向
And we get that direction and then we calculate the xy width and height
我们得到那个方向 然后我们计算xy的宽度和高度
of whatever our hurtbox.
不管我们的伤害箱是什么
Should be hitbox, is going to be for the sword.
应该是Hitbox 是要换剑的
When the sword hits something.
当剑射中某物时
So that hitbox, if it's facing the left, it's
所以Hitbox 如果它朝向左边 它是
going to be 8 pixels wide by 16 tall, which
将是8像素宽乘16高 这
is roughly the left side of the player.
大致在球员的左侧
And then we just calculate the x and y depending on which position we're in.
然后我们只计算x和y 取决于我们所处的位置
It should be roughly centered based on whatever direction the player is
它应该大致居中 基于球员的方向
looking at.
看着
And so we then instantiate that hurtbox here.
然后我们在这里实例化这个伤害框
We call it a self.swordhurtbox.
我们管它叫自助式剑术保镖
And then all we really need to do is what?
然后我们真正需要做的是什么？
In our game loop to check to see if we've hit an entity?
在我们的游戏循环中检查我们是否击中了实体？
We just need to loop over the entities in our room, the current room right?
我们只需要循环我们房间中的实体 当前房间 对吗？
Here.
这里
So every entity in the dungeon's current room.entities.
所以地牢当前房间里的每一个实体 实体
If the entity collides with our sword hurtbox, sword hitbox,
如果实体与我们的利剑伤害箱、利剑希特箱相撞
then, we saw this method before, entity damage one.
然后 我们以前见过这种方法 实体破坏一次
And then hit enemy play.
然后击打敌人的游戏
That's as simple as it is.
事情就是这么简单
And recall, in room.Lua, if an entity's health dropped below one, dropped to 0,
回想一下 在房间里 Lua 如果一个实体的生命值降到1以下 降到0
it would just trigger it to become dead.
它只会触发它变得死亡
Right?
对吗？
And so that's all we need effectively.
这就是我们有效地需要的一切
And then we have some additional logic to make sure
然后我们有一些额外的逻辑来确保
that the animation only plays one time.
动画只播放一次
And then once it has played one time, change its state to idle.
然后 一旦它播放了一次 将其状态更改为空闲
And then we can press spacebar repeatedly within that same state,
然后我们可以在相同的状态下重复按空格键
just to keep swinging if we want to.
如果我们想的话就继续摇摆
And it will just restart the animation, and restart
它将重新启动动画 然后重新启动
the hitbox being instantiated.
正在实例化的Hitbox
And so that's all we really need to do for that.
这就是我们真正需要做的一切
Now I have some lines of code here at the bottom of the sword swing
现在我在挥剑的底部有几行代码
state.lua.
国家 卢阿
And player swords, swings swords state.
和选手佩剑 摆剑状态
And what these do is sometimes it's useful
而它们所做的是有时它是有用的
when you're programming to sort of see where your collision boxes are, right?
当你编程来查看你的碰撞框在哪里时 对吗？
Because you don't necessarily know if everything's lined up perfectly.
因为你不一定知道一切是否都完美地排列在一起
When you're detecting collision between different entities,
当您检测不同实体之间的冲突时
you want to just check to see are the rectangles actually overlapping
您只需要检查一下这些矩形是否确实重叠
when this triggers?
这是什么时候触发的？
So all you need to do in order to visually see this at a glance,
所以你所需要做的就是一目了然地看到它
and you may have seen this before, in other games or debug modes of games,
你可能以前在其他游戏或调试模式的游戏中见过这种情况
is just draw a line rectangles.
就是画一条长方形的线
And then just give them the xy width and height that you want to look at, right?
然后给他们你想看的XY宽度和高度 对吗？
So here, I'm going to go ahead and save this.
所以 在这里 我将继续并保存这个
And then I'm going to run the--
然后我要运行--
I've basically uncommented it.
我基本上没有评论过它
Because by default, I don't want it showing.
因为默认情况下 我不想让它显示出来
They're pink rectangles, I don't want them displayed on screen,
它们是粉红色的矩形 我不想让它们显示在屏幕上
unless I want to do debugging.
除非我想做调试
So I'm going to uncomment them down here.
因此 我将在这里取消对它们的注释
Notice it sets the color to 255, 0 255.
请注意 它将颜色设置为255 0 255
That's magenta.
那是洋红色
I'm going to run this.
我来负责这件事
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
Turn that down a little bit.
把音量调小一点
Nothing looks particularly different.
看起来没有什么特别的不同
But when I swing my sword, notice that there's a little rectangle.
但当我挥动我的剑时 注意到有一个小矩形
And the rectangles aren't 100% perfect necessarily.
长方形也不一定是100%完美的
They give the player little bit of an advantage.
他们给了球员一点优势
Like up above, like his hitbox is barely anything.
就像上面一样 就像他的Hitbox几乎什么都不是
Up above, in the actual animation, but in the collision,
在上面 在实际动画中 但在碰撞中
I give it quite a wide berth.
我对它敬而远之
And so that's how you can, at a glance, sort of
所以这就是为什么你可以 在某种程度上
see whether your things are interacting appropriately.
看看你的东西是否有适当的相互作用
There's lines of code.
有几行代码
I did the same thing for the other states, the entity, walking,
我为其他州做了同样的事情 实体 步行
and idle states.
和空闲状态
If you want to sort of look at those, and see not only the player
如果你想看看这些 不仅能看到球员
swinging the sword, but also the other entities, and the collision boxes they
挥舞着剑 还有其他实体 以及他们的碰撞框
have, and just to check whether or not they're overlapping appropriately,
有 只是为了检查它们是否适当地重叠
or to change them, or do whatever you want with them.
或者改变它们 或者随心所欲地处理它们
But that's a nice way to do--
但这是一种很好的方式--
sometimes it's hard to debug collision if you
有时很难调试冲突 如果您
can't see exactly what's going on.
我看不清到底是怎么回事
Because it's often just in terms of xy width and height, so on and so forth,
因为它通常只是XY的宽度和高度 等等
with offsets and such.
有偏移量之类的
It can be kind of a pain and/or sort of difficult
这可能是一种痛苦和/或一种困难
to track down certain bugs that way.
以这种方式追踪特定的虫子
So just draw to the screen.
所以只要画到屏幕上就行了
You can apply that same logic to a lot of things in your game world
你可以将同样的逻辑应用到你的游戏世界中的许多事情上
that may be hidden, but you want to see sort of visually just draw shapes
这可能是隐藏的 但您希望看到某种视觉上的只是绘制形状
or draw different things for them.
或者为他们画不同的东西
So you can see what's going on.
这样你就能看到发生了什么
So that's how the hitbox and hurtbox work for our player.
对于我们的球员来说 这就是Hitbox和Hurtbox的工作方式
And you can easily just spawn more hitboxes for other entities
你可以很容易地为其他实体产生更多的点击率
if you want to.
如果你想的话
If you wanted to give them states, or maybe
如果你想给他们州 或者
you want to create projectiles that are offensive.
你想制造具有攻击性的投射物
Maybe just create projectiles, and then shoot projectiles
也许只是制造炮弹 然后发射炮弹
in a specific direction, but assign a hitbox to that projectile,
在特定方向上 但将Hitbox分配给该射弹
if you want to.
如果你想的话
Or just use the projectiles xy width and height,
或者只使用XY宽度和高度投射物
and then you can calculate a collision that way.
然后你就可以这样计算碰撞了
Just treat it like a game object, or an entity.
只需将其视为游戏对象或实体即可
It's up to you.
由你决定
Or a separate class all together.
或者一起上一个单独的班级
But that's hitboxes and hurtboxes in a nutshell.
但简而言之 这就是打击手和伤害者
Anybody have any questions as to how those sort of work?
有没有人对这些工作原理有任何疑问？
OK, cool.
好的 酷
So let's go on to the next topic.
那么 让我们继续下一个话题
So events.
所以就是这些事件
So I spoke of this earlier.
我早些时候谈到了这一点
Events are just a nice way to sort of say when something
事件只是一种很好的方式 可以说
happens, do this block of code.
如果发生这种情况 请执行此代码块
And you can do this anywhere.
你可以在任何地方做到这一点
And you can decouple it from like maybe two different objects
你可以把它从两个不同的物体中分离出来
interact with each other.
彼此互动
But you don't want them to sort of pass references
但您不希望它们传递引用
back and forth between each other, and bloat your code.
在彼此之间来回移动 并膨胀您的代码
Maybe you want the code for that check to happen not inside your main loop.
也许您希望该检查的代码发生在您的主循环中
You want to sort of abstract it out to some sort of other function,
你想把它抽象成某种其他函数
like instantiated events.
就像实例化的事件
And then have your main rendering and update logic
然后让您的主呈现和更新逻辑
be free of all this conditional stuff.
摆脱所有这些有条件的东西
So you create event.
所以你创造了事件
You say on some event, so maybe like on player walk,
你说在一些活动上 所以可能就像在运动员竞走上
and then you just update some, maybe a label
然后你只需要更新一些 也许是一个标签
on the top right of the screen, that gives the player's xy.
在屏幕的右上角 这给出了玩家的XY
And you just say that xy is equal to that player's xy.
你就说XY等于那个玩家的XY
I mean, aside from the fact that you could just literally
我的意思是 除了你可以从字面上
draw the player's xy.
画出玩家的XY
But it's the same principle.
但这是相同的原则
You can update some value somewhere separate from another entity.
您可以在独立于另一个实体的某个位置更新一些值
And then just wait for an event, arbitrarily defined event,
然后等待一个事件 任意定义的事件
that you then broadcast later.
然后你再播出
So let's say I want a broadcast swing sword.
比方说我想要一把广播摇摆剑
I have a swing sword event.
我有一场挥杆剑比赛
So whenever the player presses space, not only
因此 每当玩家按空格键时 不仅
do they do all the code that we saw before, but they swing sword.
他们做了我们之前看到的所有代码 但他们挥舞着剑
And then we say when you swing sword, pass in the xy of wherever they swung
然后我们说 当你挥舞剑时 传递他们挥舞的地方的XY
the sword.
那把剑
And so then you can say OK, on swing sword, look at all the entities,
然后你就可以说好了 在摇摆剑上 看看所有的实体
and see whether or not the hitbox at xy collides with them.
看看XY上的Hitbox是否与它们相撞
And you can sort of take out the logic from where you had it before, and put
你可以从以前的逻辑中提取出来 然后把它
it in some other centralized location.
把它放在其他集中的地方
If you want to.
如果你想的话
More representative of this model is the idea of an achievement system,
这种模式更具代表性的是成就系统的理念
where instead of every frame, and you can
而不是每一帧 你可以
have-- games have a ridiculous number of achievements.
有--游戏有许多令人难以置信的成就
Some games have like 1,000 achievements.
有些游戏有1000个这样的成绩
You don't want to put the test for every one of those 1,000
你不会想让这1000个人中的每一个
achievements necessarily inside of your update logic, right?
成就必然在你的更新逻辑之内 对吗？
You can instead just broadcast an event for all
相反 您可以只为所有人广播一项活动
of the different things that influence whether those achievements are met.
影响这些成就能否实现的不同因素
So whether a player needs to get 100 kills in a game, or 100 coins.
因此 无论一个玩家在一场比赛中需要杀死100个 还是需要100个硬币
Whether they need to jump off some ledge.
他们是否需要从悬崖上跳下来
You just have events that model all these interactions.
你只是有一些事件来模拟所有这些互动
Event on, pick-up coin, do this.
活动开始 拿起硬币 做这件事
Increment some time, some counter that's stored somewhere else.
增加一些时间 一些存储在其他地方的计数器
Event.on, kill creature.
Event.On 杀死生物
Or kill creature triggers every time you,
或者每次你杀生物的时候
literally a creature is sent from as false to dead as true.
从字面上讲 一个生物从虚假到死亡都是真实的
Maybe whenever the player jumps, you do an on jump function.
也许每当玩家跳跃时 你就会做一个跳跃功能
And then you can test to see whether or not-- in that code,
然后你可以测试一下--在这段代码中
you can test to see whether they jumped off that ledge.
你可以测试一下他们是否从悬崖上跳了下来
And then if that happens, you have your achievement system,
如果发生这种情况 你就有了你的成就系统
but you don't have all these if statements,
但您并没有所有这些if语句
and all these tests happening inside your sort of imperative game loop.
所有这些测试都发生在你的强制游戏循环中
You can just pseudo asynchronously check for all of them,
您只需伪异步地检查所有它们
given a sufficiently detailed event system in your game.
在你的游戏中有一个足够详细的事件系统
And so the library that we'll use just to show this a little bit
因此 我们将使用的库只是为了展示一点
is in the knife library, that we saw before with timer.
在刀库里 我们之前用计时器见过
Timer.on, timer.every, timer.tween.
Timer.On、Timer.Every、Timer.Tweet
In the knife library, there's a submodule
在刀库中 有一个子模块
called Event, which allows you to call event.on.
名为Event 它允许您调用Event.on
Give it a name and a function.
给它一个名称和一个函数
So on player jump, off player jump.
所以在运动员跳跃上 在运动员跳跃下
You know?
你知道?
Function.
功能
If Player.Position is by some cliff, or some area that's relevant,
如果Player.Position位于某个悬崖边 或某个相关的区域
then call this block of code.
然后调用这段代码
And increment, or set the achievement to true.
并递增 或将成就设置为真
Event.dispatch.
事件 快递
Dispatch an event when something happens.
当有事情发生时调度事件
So if a player jumps, so when they press the spacebar, event.Dispatch jump.
因此 如果玩家跳跃 那么当他们按空格键时 事件 调度跳跃
And then just whatever values that your callback function needs.
然后就是您的回调函数需要的任何值
Let's say you want to check to see what is on the cliff.
假设您想要查看悬崖上有什么
Well, if you want to check to see whether they jump off
嗯 如果你想看看他们是不是跳下
that specific cliff, you need to check their xy position, presumably,
那个特定的悬崖 你需要检查他们的XY位置 想必
so you can just pass in optional parameters via event.dispatch.
因此 只需通过Event.Dispatch传递可选参数即可
You can say OK, dispatch the event that the player jumped,
你可以说OK 调度运动员跳跃的事件
and say that the player jumped at xy.
然后说这名球员跳到了XY
And so this function call back is going to have access to the xy.
所以这个函数回调将访问xy
It's going to say OK, on jump, I say I got,
它会说好的 一跳 我说我得到了
I'm getting my callback called with player.x player.Y. And it happens to--
我的回调是由player.x player.y调用的 它碰巧--
oh, it's not at the cliff.
哦 它不在悬崖上
So nothing happens.
所以什么都没发生
Or it is the cliff, so the achievement, jump off cliff, unlocked is true.
或者是悬崖 所以成就 跳下悬崖 解锁才是真的
And test now is not happening every single frame,
现在的测试并不是每一帧都在进行
which otherwise would potentially.
否则就有可能
And it's not blocking up your update logic for your player jumping.
而且它不会阻止你的更新逻辑为您的球员跳跃
Right?
对吧？
The player, the jumping logic inside player, the player jumps state,
播放器 播放器内的跳转逻辑 播放器跳转状态
doesn't need to know--
不需要知道
doesn't need to ask whether or not we've jumped off a cliff.
不需要问我们是不是从悬崖上跳下去了
That's something that we should just delegate to our achievement file,
我们应该把它写进成就档案里
or whatever you want.
或者随便你怎么说
And that's sort of the flexibility that events afford you.
这就是事件给你的灵活性
So we use event.
所以我们使用事件
I'll touch on this a little bit briefly here.
我会在这里简单地讲一下
But basically, if we go to the player walk state on line 21.39, first of all
但基本上 如果我们在第21.39行进入参与人步行状态
we're checking for input here.
我们在检查输入
Right?
对吧？
We're just saying if we press the left, right, up, or down.
我们只是说如果我们按左 右 上 下
The direction is that walk left, walk right, so on and so forth.
方向是向左走 向右走 等等
And then what we do is we call entity walk state.update.
然后我们调用实体walk state. update
So this base walk state code that exists in entity, so that we can
所以这个存在于实体中的基本状态代码 这样我们就可以
let every single entity have this code.
让每个实体都有这个代码
All it does just check to see whether or not
它所做的只是检查
the player or entity that it belongs to hit a wall.
它所属的玩家或实体撞墙
And if it did, then set there bumped equals true.
如果是这样 那么set there bumped等于true
And what it does is just a flag that says, OK, the player bumped a wall.
它所做的只是一面旗帜 上面写着 好吧 玩家撞到了一堵墙
OK?
好吗？
Why is that relevant?
这有什么关系
Because then, after we call that, we can say, OK, if we bumped a wall,
因为在我们打完电话之后 我们可以说 好吧 如果我们撞到了一堵墙
and this only happens when the player walk state,
并且这仅在玩家处于行走状态时发生
if we're looking to the left, temporarily adjust our position.
如果我们在看左边 暂时调整一下我们的位置
Because when it bumps you, it knocks you back out back into the world.
因为当它撞到你的时候 它会把你打回原来的世界
But we're going to re-bump our position into wherever we collided.
但我们要重新调整位置到我们相撞的地方
We're going to look at every doorway, and then
我们要检查每一个入口 然后
we're going to say if we collided with that doorway, and it's open,
假设我们撞上了门 门开着
then we're going to shift it to the center of the doorway
然后我们把它移到门口的中央
so that it doesn't look as if the player is walking through the wall.
这样看起来就不会像玩家在穿墙而过
We're going to set it to wherever the wall is,
我们要把它设置到墙所在的地方
or wherever the door is, the very center of the doorway.
或者门在哪里 门口的正中央
And then we're going to call event.Dispatch shift,
然后我们要召集行动调度班
and in that direction.
朝那个方向
So shift left, shift right, shift up, and shift down.
所以左移 右移 上移 下移
And so all of these four different cases are going to say OK,
所以这四个不同的例子都会说好的
the player has hit a doorway.
玩家撞到了一个门
I have a function somewhere.
我在某个地方有一个功能
Event.on, shift down, shift left, shift right, shift up.
事件 打开 向下移动 向左移动 向右移动 向上移动
That's going to trigger what?
会触发什么？
The next room.
隔壁房间
It's going to trigger us moving to the next room, and also the next room
它会触发我们移动到下一个房间 也是下一个房间
spawning, and the camera sort of shifting position.
产卵 摄像机也在移动位置
So the code for this is in dungeon.
密码在地牢里
So we're going to go ahead and look at dungeon.
所以我们继续看地牢
So right here, on line 29 through 43, event.on,
所以就在这里 第29到43行 事件
shift left, shift right, shift up, shift down.
左移 右移 上移 下移
And what that does is we have another function called begin shifting,
它所做的是我们有另一个函数 叫做开始转移
which takes in an x and y.
它接受x和y
Negative virtual width, virtual width, negative virtual height,
负虚拟宽度 虚拟宽度 负虚拟高度
virtual height.
虚拟高度
Does anybody recall why we need to pass those numbers in there?
有人记得为什么要把这些数字传进去吗？
If we're shifting left, and we're passing a negative virtual width,
如果我们向左移动 传递一个负的虚拟宽度
what do you think that number is going to be?
你觉得会是多少
So recall every room has an adjacent offset x and y
记住每个房间都有相邻的偏移量x和y
that renders that room with that offset basically added to it.
它渲染了这个房间 基本上添加了偏移量
Its x and y.
它的x和y
So if we begin shifting to the left, negative virtual width
如果我们开始向左移动
is going to be the x offset.
就是x偏移量
Because that room needs to be rendered a screen width to the left, right?
因为那个房间需要向左渲染一个屏幕宽度 对吗？
And so on for the right, virtual width.
以此类推 以获得正确的虚拟宽度
It adds a virtual width to the x offset.
它将虚拟宽度添加到x偏移
The adjacent x offset.
相邻的x偏移
And then virtual height, negative and positive for shift up, and shift down.
然后是虚拟高度 负数和正数表示上移和下移
So begin shifting, basically the gist of this is it's a tween operation.
所以开始切换 基本上这是一个补间操作
So we start here, recall timer.tween, just takes a value and interpolates it.
所以我们从这里开始 调用timer.tween 只需要取一个值并插值
So self, we have a camera and a camera y, right?
self 我们有一个摄像机和一个摄像机y 对吧？
Going to equal shift x and shift y.
等于x和y的位移
Eventually.
最终会的
So shift x and shift y being the adjacent offset, that we're
所以移位x和移位y是相邻的偏移量 所以我们
going to need to shift the camera by.
需要把相机移开
So camera x and camera y, they both sort of zero, always.
所以X相机和Y相机 它们都是零 总是
When the room gets completely finalized.
当房间完全完工的时候
So if the shift x is virtual width, negative virtual width,
所以如果移位x是虚拟宽度 负虚拟宽度
cause we're shifting left, then it's going
因为我们在向左移动 然后它就会
to tween the camera going from right to left over the span of a second, right?
让摄像机在一秒钟内从右向左移动 对吗？
And then the player, the player x and player y,
然后玩家 玩家x和玩家y
those are basically set up here to the opposite end
这些基本上都是在这里设置在另一端
of the room, the next room.
房间的另一个房间
So if the player is going from the top of the room
因此 如果玩家从房间的顶端出发
to the bottom of the next room, it needs to get its x and y
到隔壁房间的底部 它需要得到它的x和y
put in that position, the bottom part of the next room.
放在那个位置 隔壁房间的底部
Or the left part of the next room, if they're moving from the right, right?
或者隔壁房间的左边部分 如果它们是从右边移动的 对吗？
Or the right part of they're moving from the left.
或者它们的右边部分是从左边移动的
And the bottom part if they're moving up.
最下面的部分 如果他们向上移动的话
And the up part if they're moving down.
如果他们向下移动 则是向上的部分
So that's all that does.
所以这就是所有的作用
Puts them in the right position, on the next room.
把他们放在正确的位置 在隔壁房间
Tweens both of them, the camera and the player,
他们两个人 摄像机和播放器
because the player needs to keep moving to the next room.
因为球员需要不停地移动到隔壁房间
And the camera needs to shift up.
而且相机需要向上移动
When it's finished, we call finished shifting,
当它完成时 我们称其为完成移位
which is just a function that says basically everything to 0.
这只是一个函数 基本上所有的东西都是0
It sets the current room to the next room.
它将当前房间设置为下一个房间
It sets the camera x and all that stuff all to 0,
它将摄像机x和所有这些东西都设置为0
and then all the entities and objects there, it all gets set to 0.
然后所有实体和对象都设置为0
So they are offset to 0.
因此 它们的偏移量为0
So that everything is basically right at 0.0
所以一切基本上都是正确的 在0.0
again, just like it was at the very beginning.
再一次 就像一开始一样
And then last but not least, when we get into the new room,
最后但同样重要的是 当我们进入新房间时
we start with the doors all open.
我们一开始就把所有的门都打开
And then when we get into the room here, because this is all
然后当我们走进这里的房间时 因为这就是
done in the finished function, recall, this
在完成的函数中完成 调用 这
will only happen after the tween is completed.
只有在补间结束后才会发生
Every doorway is going to get set to false.
每个入口都将被设置为False
Open equals false.
打开等于假
So all the doors will close as soon as we get into the next room,
所以我们一进隔壁房间所有的门都会关上
after we've performed the tween operation.
在我们做完补丁手术之后
And then we'll play a door sound.
然后我们将播放一段门声
So that's the code involved in actually doing the shift operation.
这就是实际执行移位操作所涉及的代码
So we were able to trigger it.
所以我们能够触发它
We don't have to necessarily do that code from the player walk state.
我们不一定要在玩家漫游状态下执行该代码
We just say if the players collide with the doorway,
我们只是说 如果球员撞到门口
then dispatch an event that is handled by dungeon.
然后调度一个由地牢处理的事件
Because dungeon has access to current room, next room, and all the stuff
因为地牢有权进入现在的房间 隔壁的房间 以及所有的东西
that it needs to actually perform that transition.
它需要真正地进行这种转变
So we have the two that are sort of decoupled but they work well
所以我们有两个分离的 但它们工作得很好
in tandem with one another.
彼此齐头并进
So anybody have questions as to sort of how this works?
那么 有谁对这是如何运作的有疑问吗？
OK.
好的
That's essentially the dungeon scrolling.
这基本上就是地下城的滚动
It's a tween operation.
这是一次青少年行动
It's a camera, a temporary room gets rendered.
这是一个摄像头 一个临时的房间被渲染
We move to a temporary room, everything gets set back to 0.
我们搬到一个临时房间 一切都恢复到0
And then it's just a wild loop of that sort of behavior, effectively.
然后 这实际上就是那种行为的疯狂循环
And we use the event library to sort of clean up that whole aspect.
我们使用事件库在某种程度上清理了整个方面
And sort of screen scrolling here, just another demonstration.
屏幕在这里滚动 这是另一个演示
We went over it in detail, but this is a nice GIF
我们详细地看过了 但这是一个很好的GIF
I found that sort of encapsulates what that means.
我发现这在某种程度上概括了这意味着什么
Stenciling is something that we saw earlier.
模版是我们之前看到的东西
And if we look at this as a stencil, so we
如果我们把它看作一张模板 那么我们
can pretend that these are the circle of the heart,
可以假装这些是心脏的圆圈
and that rectangle are a stencil.
而那个长方形是一张模板
And then we want to draw this gray rectangle on top of those stencils.
然后我们想在这些模板上画一个灰色的矩形
We can use the stencil to mask out specific parts, which
我们可以使用模板来遮盖特定的部分 这
would otherwise be pretty tough to do.
否则很难做到这一点
I mean, it's hard to necessarily, maybe individually
我是说 很难有必要 也许是个别
render pixels, or create a shape that sort of looks like this.
渲染像素 或创建类似如下的形状
Much easier for a lot of very interesting visual effects
对于许多非常有趣的视觉效果来说要容易得多
to use a stencil of arbitrary shape and size.
使用任意形状和大小的模板
And you can use images, too.
你也可以使用图像
You can use images of stencils, to create some pretty cool effects.
你可以使用模具的图像 来创造一些非常酷的效果
We went over it before, when I talked about the archway.
我们以前讨论过它 当我谈到拱门的时候
So I won't go over into much more detail.
所以我不会过多地详述
But again, you can look at that in the, where was it exactly?
但是 你可以再一次看到 它到底在哪里？
It was in the room function, room class, sorry.
它在房间的功能里 房间里 对不起
Down here at the bottom.
就在这下面的底部
So lines to 213 to 229 recall they're a stencil function.
所以从213行到229行 记住它们是模板函数
The couple functions in particular that you need to use
这两个函数尤其是您需要使用的
are love.graphics.stencil which draws the stencils, and then
是love.graph 绘制模板的模板 然后
love.graphics.setstenciltest which compares
Love.graph ics.setstenciltest 比较
the stencil values to some value, and draws them
模板将值设置为某个值 并绘制它们
whether or not that condition is true.
无论该条件是否为真
So we have our function here, which draws four rectangles.
所以我们在这里有我们的函数 画四个矩形
Those are all the archways.
这些都是拱门
It replaces any pixels that get drawn to those rectangles with the value 1.
它将绘制到这些矩形的所有像素替换为值1
The stencil value 1, so stencil value is just
模板值为1 因此模板值为
like a hidden value that determines whether a image will get
类似于一个隐藏值 它确定图像是否将
drawn if it's being stenciled or not.
不管它是不是被模压过的
Set stencil test means that we're looking for anything less than 1.
设定模板测试意味着我们正在寻找小于1的任何值
And we'll draw that.
我们会画出来的
And because the player is going to be 1 if it's
因为玩家将会是1 如果它是
on any of those stencil rectangles, it will not
在任何这些模板矩形上 它都不会
draw the player if it overlaps with those stencil rectangles.
如果球员与这些模板矩形重叠 请绘制该球员
And so that's in general how it works.
这就是它通常的工作原理
And you can do, there's a lot different comparisons.
你可以这样做 有很多不同的比较
You can do greater than 1.
您可以执行大于1的操作
You can do iterative stenciling so that you can increment of value.
你可以做迭代模版 这样你就可以增加价值
You can have simple values go between 0 and 255.
您可以使用介于0和255之间的简单值
There's a lot of interesting effects you can get with that.
有很多有趣的效果 你可以用它
But the general use that we just saw is set the values to one,
但我们刚才看到的一般用法是将值设置为1
and check to see whether they're less than 1, if you want to draw them.
如果要绘制它们 请检查它们是否小于1
If you want to not draw them.
如果你不想画它们的话
Does anybody have questions how stenciling works,
有没有人对模版制作有疑问
and how these functions work?
以及这些功能是如何工作的？
Yeah?
嗯?
AUDIENCE: So like having stat stencil cover up the door?
观众：所以就像用Stat模具把门遮住一样？
So when you draw the player, you won't actually
所以当你画玩家的时候 你不会真的
draw on the stencil, [INAUDIBLE].
在模板上画 [INAUDIBLE]
COLTON OGDEN: Yes.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
So it's like having the stencil rectangles go over the doorway,
所以这就像是让模板矩形越过门口
so that the player will not get drawn when it's underneath them.
这样当球在他们下面时 球员就不会被抽到
If I go back to a slide that has it.
如果我回到有它的幻灯片上
The stencils are here.
模板在这里
Right?
对吗？
I had to go through and figure out the exact xy that I needed for them.
我必须通过并弄清楚我需要的确切的XY
And there is a--
而且还有一个--
what you can do is you can take that stencil function that
您可以做的是 您可以将模板函数
draws the rectangles, and you can just take it out of the stencil test,
画出矩形 然后你就可以把它从模具测试中拿出来
and see.
然后你看
You will actually be able to see where the exact rectangles are.
实际上 您将能够看到确切的矩形在哪里
Because then it will just literally draw the rectangles.
因为那样它就会直接画出长方形
But here, basically right between here and where it would be on the next room.
但在这里 基本上就在这里和隔壁房间的位置之间
So that when we go from here over into the next room, it's still
所以当我们从这里走到隔壁房间时 它仍然是
stencils them.
用模板来刻印它们
Right here, the player is going to go over them.
就在这里 球员要检查他们
It's going to set its stencil value to 1.
它会将其模板值设置为1
It's checking for anything less than 1 to render.
它正在检查要呈现的任何小于1的值
So it's going to fail the test, and it's going
所以它不会通过测试 它会
to not draw that player at that point.
在这一点上不会抽到那个球员
So it's effectively just masking out the player,
因此 它实际上只是掩盖了玩家
because we're assigning it to the right stencil value,
因为我们给它分配了正确的模板值
and we're doing the right comparison for it.
我们对此进行了正确的比较
But yeah, that's effectively it.
但是 是的 实际上就是这样
Just using it to, because we were in a situation
只是用它来 因为我们处于一种情况
where our tiles didn't cleanly lend themselves to drawing over
我们的瓷砖不能干净利落地画出来
the player, which you could do.
球员 你可以做到的
You could draw the shadow part underneath the archway part,
你可以在拱门下面画阴影部分
and then just change the rendering order.
然后只需更改渲染顺序
But the spreadsheet that we had didn't afford us that flexibility.
但我们拥有的电子表格并没有为我们提供这种灵活性
So we went with a little more interesting stenciling approach
因此 我们采用了更有趣的模版方法
to getting it done.
为完成任务干杯
We looked at this earlier.
我们之前看过这个
So game design via data, rather than a bunch of logic.
所以游戏设计靠的是数据 而不是一堆逻辑
So the more you can sort of get towards modeling your anything in your game
所以你越能在游戏中对你的任何东西进行建模
like data, like this, the more flexible your engine is,
像这样的数据 你的引擎越灵活
the easier it is for people to mod your game.
人们就越容易修改你的游戏
Which is hugely important.
这一点非常重要
And the easier it is for you to let designers
你越容易让设计师
take charge of actually creating assets for your game.
负责为你的游戏创造资产
So here we've created an arbitrary collection of data,
所以这里我们创建了一个任意的数据集合
and you can get as complex with this as you want to.
你可以想怎么复杂就怎么复杂
The only thing that really matters is whether your game engine
唯一真正重要的是你的游戏引擎
supports those fields, and acts on those fields accordingly.
支持这些字段 并相应地对这些字段进行操作
But once it does, I mean, the more things
但一旦发生 我是说
you add, the more possibilities you have for adding new things.
你就越有可能添加新的东西
So goblin, we have health, strength.
所以地精 我们有健康 力量
So strength should be accounted for in our game engine.
因此 我们的游戏引擎应该考虑到强度
And this is, we're talking in just the general abstract sense now.
这是 我们现在谈论的只是一般的抽象意义
Let's say we're like making an RPG or something.
比如说我们在做一个RPG什么的
Or maybe this is part of our Zelda game.
或许这是我们塞尔达游戏的一部分
If we got a little bit more detailed with it.
如果我们再详细一点
But goblin is going to be a creature that has 10 health.
但是地精将是一个有10点生命的生物
It's got two strength, so these values will
它有两个强度 所以这些值
get loaded when it's created as an entity,
当它被创建为一个实体时被加载
and strength is some value that our engine
力量是我们的引擎
needs to apply to anything that it decides to attack.
需要适用于它决定攻击的任何东西
Right?
对吧？
You could do the same thing with defense.
你可以在防守上做同样的事情
You could create arbitrary things.
你可以创造任意的东西
It's got a goblin texture.
有妖精的质感
So that's the sprite.
这就是雪碧
We've defined some animations here, which
我们在这里定义了一些动画
you've already seen how to instantiate those in our game engine.
你已经看到了如何在我们的游戏引擎中实例化它们
Maybe it starts off with a club weapon.
可能是从棍棒开始的
And you can also reference other sort of Lua files
你也可以参考其他类型的Lua文件
that have these definitions, if you have maybe a weapons defs file.
如果你有武器定义文件的话
You could index into weapons defs club, and then that club item
你可以索引到武器defs俱乐部 然后那个俱乐部项目
will maybe have a bunch of its own characteristics
也许会有一些自己的特点
that when your game engine is loading this goblin def,
当你的游戏引擎加载这个地精def时
it loads in the club def as well, and instantiates a bunch of qualities
它也会加载club def 并实例化一堆特性
onto that entity, or that item, that then have
到那个实体上 或者那个项目上
behavior relevant to your game engine.
与游戏引擎相关的行为
Aggressive is true.
侵略性是真的
So if something is entity.Aggressive, then maybe it's AI
所以如果某个东西是实体的 侵略性的 那么它可能就是人工智能
will seek out the player.
会去找玩家
Right?
对吧？
And you can set it to false.
您可以将其设置为False
So now you can differentiate between entities that chase the player,
所以现在你可以区分追逐玩家的实体
and entities that are sort of docile, and just do their own random thing.
和一些温顺的实体 只是做他们自己随机的事情
Sleeps at night.
晚上睡觉
Maybe your game has a day/night cycle.
也许你的游戏有一个昼夜循环
Maybe some entities stay awake, and some go into a sleep state, right?
也许有些实体保持清醒 有些进入睡眠状态 对吗？
So it will look and say OK, it's nighttime,
所以它看起来会说好的 现在是晚上
does the entity sleep at night?
这个实体在晚上睡觉吗？
If it does, OK.
如果是这样的话 没问题
Then entity change state, sleep, right?
然后实体改变状态 休眠 对吗？
And then during the day, when the day happens,
然后在白天 当白天发生的时候
you'll do the same thing in reverse.
您将以相反的方式做同样的事情
You'll say if the entity sleeps at night,
你会说如果实体在晚上睡觉
then you say entity.awake is true.
然后你说实体 觉醒是真的
Or whatever it is.
或者什么都行
Change state awake, or idle, or walking.
将状态更改为清醒、空闲或行走
And then flammable.
然后是易燃物
Maybe you have weapons that shoot damage, or shoot fire.
也许你有武器可以造成伤害 或者开火
Or maybe you have torches that shoot fire, or some--
或者你有可以发射火焰的手电筒 或者一些--
maybe you're in a level that's like lava.
也许你处在像熔岩一样的水平
And you know, if you touch one of the tiles, it has a flammable effect.
你知道 如果你触摸其中一块瓷砖 它就会产生易燃效果
And if it's flammable, may be your status equals flammable.
如果它是易燃的 可能你的状态也是易燃的
You take damage over time.
随着时间的推移 你会受到伤害
And you change your animation.
然后你改变你的动画
Maybe you'd get tinted red, or something like that.
也许你会被染成红色 或者类似的颜色
But thinking about all these different possibilities,
但考虑到所有这些不同的可能性
like what your engine is capable of, you can create pretty much arbitrarily
就像你的引擎所能做的一样 你几乎可以任意地创造
complex data structures and entities, and items,
复杂的数据结构和实体 以及项
and whatever you want in your game, without having
和你想要的任何东西 而不是
to create a goblin class.
来创建一个妖精职业
Or a skeleton class.
或者是一个骨架类
Or a arbitrarily complex creature class.
或者是一个任意复杂的生物类别
You just compose your creature with attributes and model
你只需要用属性和模型组合你的生物
its behavior that way.
它的行为就是这样的
Composition over inheritance, which we talked about last week,
组成重于继承 我们上周谈到了
is very valuable in game design.
在游戏设计中非常有价值
And that's what Unity's game engine sort of approaches.
这就是Unity的游戏引擎所采用的方法
Because entity is a purely entity component system,
由于实体是纯实体组件系统
whereby entities are modeled as collections of components
其中实体被建模为组件的集合
that each do something.
每个人都做了一些事情
And we can sort of almost think of these as components, too.
我们也几乎可以把它们看作是组件
Albeit in a much simpler sort of representation.
尽管是在一种简单得多的表现形式中
Does anybody have questions of this, or like why it's useful,
有没有人对此有疑问 或者为什么它有用
or anything like that?
或诸如此类的事？
OK.
好的
So the last thing I wanted to talk about today, and I saw one or two students
所以我今天最不想谈的就是 我看到了一两个学生
were mentioning how they wished they knew, or wish we
提到他们多么希望自己知道 或者多么希望我们
talked about a little bit more how programming was done back in the day.
更多地谈了一下当时是如何进行编程的
So I'm not an expert, necessarily, in programming 6502 assembly,
所以我不一定是6502汇编编程方面的专家
which is what the NES is written in.
这就是NES是用来写的
There are a lot of people that are very good at it.
有很多人在这方面做得很好
But there's a few links here.
但这里有一些联系
So in the slides, if you wanted to look at the slides on the website,
所以在幻灯片中 如果你想看网站上的幻灯片
Homebrew is actually quite a popular thing amongst certain communities
实际上 自制酒在某些社区中相当受欢迎
online.
上网
And what it is essentially getting compilers
以及它本质上为编译器带来了什么
that will compile source code for some arbitrary processor, or development
这将为某些任意处理器或开发编译源代码
environment from some arbitrary computer system.
来自某个任意计算机系统的环境
Like the NES, which was a 8-bit microprocessor based machine
像NES一样 它是一台基于8位微处理器的机器
with its own set of interesting hardware.
拥有自己的一套有趣的硬件
It allowed you to compile the assembly for that
它允许您为此编译程序集
and actually run it via a program called an emulator.
并通过一个名为模拟器的程序实际运行它
And an emulator just allows you to run ROM images, or just arbitrary data
而仿真器只允许您运行ROM映像 或者只运行任意数据
that maps to the machine instructions of some system
它映射到某个系统的机器指令
that the emulator has emulated via virtual machine.
仿真器已经通过虚拟机进行了仿真
And so if you wanted to look into it a little bit more in detail,
因此 如果你想更详细地研究它
there's a couple of links here.
这里有几个链接
So NES.wiki has got a bunch of great links.
所以 NES.wiki有很多很棒的链接
There's a Programming Guide that kind of goes
有一本编程指南是这样写的
over the basics of how to do some 6502 assembly as well as with the NES,
关于如何进行一些6502组装以及如何使用NES的基础知识
and its particular hardware.
以及它的特殊硬件
And then the compiler that most people use for this is called CC 65,
然后大多数人使用的编译器被称为CC 65
which is a 65 02 assembly compiler.
它是一个65 02汇编语言编译器
And so this is an example of some source code.
这是一些源代码的一个例子
It's a little bit tough to read.
这本书读起来有点难
But I can't zoom in, I don't think.
但我不能放大 我想不是
But the gist of it is you have a lot of--
但大意是你有很多--
and here, actually I could pull it up online.
在这里 实际上我可以在网上调出它
Le me try.
让我试试看
Super Mario disassembly.
超级马里奥反汇编
So go here.
那就去这里吧
This is on Github.
这是在Github上
So somebody decompiled, basically, or disassembled rather,
所以有人反编译 基本上 或者说反汇编
took the bytes that represent all the machine code and the ROM image of Super
获取代表Super的所有机器代码和ROM镜像的字节
Mario Bros and then just converted it back to assembly language,
Mario Bros 然后将其转换回汇编语言
and then added comments to it.
然后给它添加了评论
Because I won't go into too much detail about what assembly is,
因为我不会太详细地讲什么是组装
and how it works, but essentially it's just
以及它是如何工作的 但本质上说 它只是
a layer directly above machine code where the keywords
直接位于机器代码上方的一层 其中关键字
map to essentially what are bytes in memory
映射到内存中的基本字节数
that are actually program instructions.
它们实际上是程序指令
And that influence the behavior of your CPU such that you get programs.
这会影响你的CPU的行为 这样你就可以得到程序
And that's what c is layered on top of, an in every language thereof,
而这就是c语言的基础 在它的每一种语言中
thereafter.
之后
So if I zoom in here, see if I can.
所以如果我放大这里 看看我能不能
It's being a little slow.
它有点慢了
But it's letting me--
但它让我--
so here we can see.
所以我们可以在这里看到
I think it's lagging because the file is just so large.
我认为它滞后是因为文件太大了
It's like 14,000 lines of code.
这就像是14000行代码
Because the thing about assembly is assembly is a very, very long.
因为组装是一件很长很长的事情
Because there are so many--
因为有太多的--
you need to have, just like really slowly.
你需要有 就像真的很慢
Zooming in infinitely.
无限放大
There are just so many steps you need to do in order
你需要做的步骤太多了
to achieve the same thing that you get in a high level language like C,
为了实现像C这样的高级语言所实现的相同功能
or even languages higher than that.
甚至比这更高的语言
Taking a lot of things for granted, especially things like loading
认为很多事情都是理所当然的 特别是像加载这样的事情
registers.
寄存器
So every CPU has got a series of registers that can store values,
所以每个CPU都有一系列可以存储数值的寄存器
and then the CPU has logic that you can basically
然后CPU有逻辑 你基本上可以
say OK, if the value in register a is greater than or equal to some value,
说OK 如果寄存器A中的值大于或等于某个值
then branch to this sequence of the assembly code.
然后转移到汇编代码的这个序列
And often you'll have to do things like and/or operations on byte level,
通常 您必须在字节级执行和/或操作
just on bytes.
仅以字节为单位
Like right here, we can see we're ending the value 3 on whatever
就像这里 我们可以看到我们正在结束值3
is in register a.
在登记簿a中
Like I said, don't intend to get too much into what assembly is.
就像我说的 不要太过沉迷于什么是组装
But for those curious as to how games were implemented in the '80s, and even
但对于那些好奇游戏是如何在80年代实现的 甚至
the early '90s, it was all in assembly language.
90年代早期 都是用汇编语言
Because assembly language is you're literally
因为汇编语言就是你
programming the CPU of whatever machine you're trying to program.
对你要编程的机器的CPU进行编程
And that's how you get as much efficiency as possible.
这就是你如何获得尽可能多的效率
If you know your computing, environment you know what your CPU is capable of.
如果你了解你的计算环境 你就知道你的CPU能做什么
The thing about compiling a language like C, or C++, or Java,
关于编译像C C++ 或Java这样的语言
which is even higher of an abstraction than those,
这是一个比那些更高的抽象
is you're allowing sort of algorithms to do the work for you.
就是你允许某种算法为你做这些工作
You're allowing algorithms to take your source code
你允许算法把你的源代码
and turn it into this, basically.
然后把它变成这样
A layer lower than this, effectively.
比这层低一层 有效
This is an intermediary level that it does generate.
这是它所产生的一个中间层次
But suffice to say, in the '80s and '90s,
但可以说 在80年代和90年代
C compilers were not as good as humans were in creating games,
C编译器在创建游戏方面不如人类
especially to do a lot of the tricky things that they needed to do,
特别是做很多他们需要做的棘手的事情
in order to get them working efficiently on processors that were, at the time,
为了让它们在处理器上高效地工作 在当时
one to three megahertz in speed.
1到3兆赫的速度
Which now we have like three gigahertz processors, and it's no big deal.
现在我们有三个千兆赫的处理器 这没什么大不了的
But that is effectively, that's sort of a window
但这实际上是一个窗口
into what it was like developing games in the '80s and '90s.
80年代和90年代开发游戏的情况
And then in the '90s, with like things like N64 Playstation 1,
然后在90年代 像N64 Playstation 1这样的东西
going onto Playstation 2, and so forth, it was typically done in a language
在Playstation 2上 等等 它通常是用一种语言完成的
like C or C++.
比如C或C++
Sometimes with some variants.
有时候有一些变种
Certain consoles, like the PS3 has a notoriously difficult graphics
某些游戏机 如PS3有一个臭名昭著的困难的图形
processor to program.
处理器编程
So a lot of PS3 three teams needed to program in assembly,
所以很多PS3的三个团队需要在汇编中编程
even at the time, which was 2007, 2009.
即使是在2007年 2009年
But that's, in a nutshell, what it's like programming the 65 02.
但这就是 简而言之 它就像编程的65 02
So if you want, those links up above, it's
如果你想看上面的链接
a pretty enlightening experience actually digging
一个很有启发性的经历
into that sort of thing, and trying to make sense of what the assembly does.
并试图理解大会的工作
It's quite difficult, and quite burdensome because of how long
这很困难 也很繁重 因为
these programs are, and just how minute each individual instruction is.
这些程序是什么 每个指令是多么的微小
Like just checking, just loading a value into a register,
就像只是检查 只是把一个值加载到一个寄存器
just to do a loop often will just be iteratively loading a value
循环通常只是迭代地加载一个值
into a register.
到一个寄存器
And then like performing some operation, or calculation, off of that.
然后像执行一些操作 或计算 从那里
And then branching to some other loop of code.
然后分支到其他代码循环
A lot of that can be condensed into like just a couple of lines of C,
很多内容都可以压缩成几行C语言
or even fewer lines of Lua.
或者更少的Lua行
So a lot more of a burden but there is insight.
所以更多的负担 但有洞察力
Definitely some insight into digging a little deeper
肯定是对深入调查的一些见解
and sort of looking there.
看向那里
So once again, those are the links on the NES dev wiki.
这些都是NES开发wiki上的链接
Wiki.NESdev.com if you're interested in looking at that.
Wiki.NESdev.com如果你有兴趣看的话
In Assignment 5, like you did in Assignment 4,
在作业5中 就像你在作业4中做的那样
you can create a game object that's consumable.
你可以创建一个可消耗的游戏对象
And feel free to use code from Assignment 4 to do this.
可以随意使用作业4中的代码来完成此任务
When like you define your on consume function,
当你定义你的消费函数时
if you're going to adopt the same model as the last assignment, then any ideas
如果你们打算采用和上次作业相同的模式 那么有什么想法吗
as to what we need to do?
我们该怎么做
Probably just add the opposite of damage the entity, right?
可能只是增加了破坏实体的反义词 对吧？
We want to add hearts.
我们想添加心脏
We want to add HP to it.
我们希望将HP添加到其中
And you'll see in the distro that health is modeled as an even number,
你会看到在发行版中health被建模为偶数
because every one digit is half a heart.
因为每一个数字都是半颗心
Yes.
是的
AUDIENCE: Can you give a negative number to [INAUDIBLE]??
问：你能给一个负数吗？
COLTON OGDEN: You can.
科尔顿·奥格登：你可以
And that will effectively be the same thing, too.
这实际上也是同样的事情
So.
是的
The second part is including pots.
第二部分是包括锅
So there are pots in the sprite sheet.
所以在精灵表中有罐子
So these should be solid.
所以这些应该是实心的
So when the player interacts with them, he
当玩家与他们互动时
should be bumped out of where he was.
应该把他赶出去
Allow the player to lift them.
让玩家举起它们
So there's an animation in the sprite sheet that will actually allow--
所以在精灵表中有一个动画 它实际上允许--
that shows the player lifting up the pot.
显示玩家举起罐子
So you probably need a new state, player lift pot state.
所以你可能需要一个新的状态 玩家举罐状态
Walk with pot state.
与大麻州同行
Whatever you want to define it as.
不管你怎么定义它
But you'll need basically to have those two in order to get this to work.
但你基本上需要有这两个人 才能让这件事起作用
What's one thing that we'll need to do in order for the player
我们需要做的一件事是什么？
to lift the pot.
抬起锅来
Any ideas?
有什么主意吗？
Besides the rendering aspect of it, when the player walks around, for example,
除了渲染方面 例如 当玩家四处走动时
what needs to happen?
需要采取什么措施？
If he's holding the pot.
如果他拿着罐子的话
AUDIENCE: He's slower.
观众：他比较慢
COLTON OGDEN: You can make him slower.
科尔顿·奥格登：你可以让他慢一点
Yeah, that's possible.
是的 这是有可能的
That's not required for the assignment.
这不是作业所必需的
More fundamental than that.
比这更基本的
The pot needs to track the player's location, right?
赌注需要追踪玩家的位置 对吗？
It needs to be relative to the player's location.
它需要相对于球员的位置
So keep the pot probably above the player by some amount.
因此 保持赌注可能比玩家高出一小部分
I won't be too picky as to how you implement that.
对于如何实现这一点 我不会太挑剔
But the pot needs to track the player.
但博彩需要跟踪玩家
Which is this next point, actually.
实际上 这就是下一点
And the walking animations, like I said, should
行走的动画 就像我说的 应该
change while they're carrying it.
在他们拿着的时候换衣服
Allow the player, lastly, to throw the pot.
最后 允许玩家投掷水壶
So when you throw the pot, basically turn the pot into a projectile.
所以当你扔罐子的时候 基本上就是把罐子变成了抛射物
If it hits one of the walls, break it.
如果它撞到了其中一面墙 就把它打破
You can either just despawn it instantly, or have some animation.
您可以只是立即取消绘制 或有一些动画
It's up to you.
由你决定
But just, if it hits a wall, despawn it.
但是 如果它撞到了墙 就放弃它
Trigger it to-- maybe just trigger it to some values, false.
触发它--可能只是触发它到一些值 假
Render is false, whatever you want to do.
渲染是假的 无论你想做什么
If it hits an enemy, it should damage the enemy by one,
如果它击中敌人 它应该会对敌人造成一次伤害
just like we've seen already.
就像我们已经看到的一样
And if it travels farther than four tiles,
如果它运行的距离超过四块瓷砖
in addition to also hitting one of the walls, then destroy it too.
除了还撞到其中一堵墙 然后把它也毁了
So those are the main components for Assignment 5.
这些都是作业5的主要组成部分
And the ways that which you achieve most of it's fairly flexible.
而你实现大部分目标的方式是相当灵活的
But yeah, that's Lecture 5, Legend of Zelda.
但没错 这就是第五课 塞尔达传奇
So thanks for coming.
所以感谢你们的光临
I'll see you next time.
下次见